<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <ns0:title type="html">BotPress</ns0:title>
    <ns0:generator>Blogger</ns0:generator>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
    <ns0:updated>2018-02-03T01:56:20Z</ns0:updated>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2540</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;So many people have a smartphone. Some of the biggest phones on the market is the iPhone, created by Apple or android phones such as Samsung or Google. Many of us like to download various apps or music we can enjoy on the go. The app store has a crazy number of more than 1,5 million apps. Most of these apps are available on any device but some are specifically designed for one model, such as the iPhone. Quite often we can find apps we like for free. Although, most of these apps now offer in-app purchases (after all, nothing is truly free!) Some apps must be paid for. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt; &lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Users can download or buy apps that will download directly onto your device including; iOS device; iPads, iPhones, or iPod touch. These are bought directly from the app store on your device. If your iPhone is linked to cloud and you have an iPad, it is possible to download an app on one device and it appear on both. Fortunately, it’s usually easy to download and use the various apps but what happens if it doesn’t work?&lt;img class="size-medium wp-image-1151 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/your-puchase-could-not-be-completed-300x237.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="237" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Occasionally when you try to download an app, a message will come up on your phone which will say it is unable to download or buy/renew a subscription. “your purchase was unsuccessful” why does this happen?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Your Apple ID may be associated with too many credit cards.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Sometimes, we have various credit and debit cards we use to pay for various things and sadly, we misplace our cards. Consequently, we then receive a new card and add it to our payment options. However, often, we forget to remove previous or unused cards. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Your credit card may be blocked&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Your credit or debit card may be blocked for a variety of reasons. Maybe you have overspent on your credit or you haven’t got the funds you thought. In this instance, it may be advisable to call your bank.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;You are trying to buy something that you are not allowed to buy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Some apps have an age restriction of on them or need parental consent if you under the age of sixteen or eighteen. Some apps are not available in your country or have not yet been established. For example, some apps may be available in America but are not available in UK. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Your account information may not be matching the credit card information on file with your bank.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Maybe you have moved to a new house or changed your billing address? If your details are different than the details the bank have, purchases will be unsuccessful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fix it!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;In instances where the purchase does not work, it is best to contact the makers of the app store, like Apple.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;To do this you can visit; Apple.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Or go into the iTunes store, select the option that says, ‘Purchase and Billing then select “unable to purchase from the iTunes store”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;You can contact apple by email, online chat or by scheduling a call&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Sometimes, you may want to troubleshoot before contacting Apple&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Go into settings &amp;gt; iTunes and App Stores and access your Apple ID, make sure all your information is updated and correct&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Sometimes restarting your device is sufficient&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Logging out and the signing into the iTunes store, may correct any errors. You can this by going into settings &amp;gt; iTunes and App stores and access your Apple ID &amp;gt; then sign out. Wait a minute and sign back in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span lang="en-US"&gt;Or you can check your restrictions. If you have enabled restrictions, it is best to check that you can access the iTunes store and make purchases or (in-app purchases&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 12:54 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:34Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Your Purchase Could Not Be Completed Apple IOS , Fix</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2540" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2540" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2541</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;When the iPhone was first introduced the Apple would not consider using the Bluetooth technology for the purpose of file sharing or data exchange of any kind. At the time, Apple stated their concerns of personal data security as the principal reasoning behind the decision and they stuck to it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Later as the iPhone continued to offer new features with each update, “Airdrop” was introduced. With Airdrop iOS compatible and macOS devices could share files of almost any type between them with using an encrypted protocol via “Airdrop”. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Since being introduced with iOS 7 and OS X Lion Airdrop has had its ups and downs with users. Because this feature does not always work as expected, the result has been negative feedback from Apple users. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;The technology Airdrop relies on is a combination of the onboard Wi-Fi chip and Bluetooth 4.0 LE and it can sometimes be difficult to troubleshoot in the conventional troubleshooting approaches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;There are still a number of options before you throw in the towel and head to the Genius Bar of your local Apple Store. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you have exhausted all of your regular fix its for Airdrop on your Mac, iPhone or iPad, here is a list of 11 Ways to Fix Airdrop:&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1090 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/Best-Ways-To-fix-Airdrop.png" alt="" width="560" height="315" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Checking the Bluetooth and Connectivity of Your Device&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Because Airdrop relies on Wi-Fi and Bluetooth, checking connectivity should be one of the first things you do on both devices that are trying to connect. This seems obvious now but is often overlooked before frustration levels break. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Start by making sure the Bluetooth is actually enabled on both devices. To do this for macOS check the &lt;b&gt;menu bar&lt;/b&gt; for the status and for iOS check in the &lt;b&gt;Control Center&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you find that either the Bluetooth the or the Wi-Fi was not connected, re-connect them now and give Airdrop another try. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Although it should be noticeable when checking to see if the Bluetooth was enabled, double check now to see if your device is in &lt;b&gt;Airplane Mode&lt;/b&gt;. This can be done by going to Settings in an iOS device and make sure the switch for Airplane mode is off. Confirm or move the switch to the on position and give Airdrop a try.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="2"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Status of Do Not Disturb&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Because of the complex manner an iOS or macOS can be customized for more personal use, there are a number of things that are overridden without thought when using the Do Not Disturb feature of either system. It really means “Do Not Disturb”.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;When an incoming transfer is being received from Airdrop a notification is sent to the receiving device and the recipient must accept the file. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If either an iOS or mac are in DND they will not receive the notification. This might just be something you forgot was engaged. Check and make sure your device is not set to DND and try Airdrop again.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1092 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/do-not-disturb-tab-iphone-airdrop.png" alt="" width="300" height="219" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This can be done on an iOS device by going to the &lt;b&gt;Control Center&lt;/b&gt; and making sure the&lt;b&gt; moon icon &lt;/b&gt;(Do Not Disturb) is not in the on position.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1094 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/disable-do-not-disturb.png" alt="" width="300" height="214" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To turn off the DND on a macOS in the &lt;b&gt;Notifications Panel&lt;/b&gt; if you have it set up or through &lt;b&gt;Notifications System Preferences&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Make note, if you have a scheduled “DND” time frame for your device, airdrop likely will not work during those hours. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="3"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make Sure the Receiving iOS Device’s Screen is On&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Going back to the previous step for troubleshooting, it is helpful if the screen of the receiving iOS device is on. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Because the notification is prompted on the receiving device to accept the file transfer, it is useful to verify the notification can be seen and responded to in a timely manner which if not, will result in a failed attempt to connect. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Notifications from Airdrop may not always turn on the screen of your iOS device. Before you transfer any data, make sure the receiving iOS device screen is on. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Please note this tip only applies to iOS devices. With macOS the screen status doesn’t matter because the system is not in sleep mode. Airdrop will cause a notification on a locked screen of macOS automatically. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="4"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Is Airdrop On? Is it Visible?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;There are three possible settings for Airdrop with different levels of visibility to the sender from the receiver. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Everyone: &lt;/b&gt;When in this setting anyone nearby with Airdrop on can see your device is enabled as well. This is typically the recommended setting as you cannot receive a file transfer without first accepting it. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Contacts Only: &lt;/b&gt;Only your contacts with their Airdrop enabled nearby can discover your device and even then it is only if both devices have each other’s phone number or Apple ID and be signed into iCloud to work. This is a layer of additional security that can be confusing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Off: &lt;/b&gt;Your device cannot be discovered by anyone however, you can still send files to other enabled and visible devices. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;These are troubleshooting tips for the receiving device. As a preference you should have this should be set to &lt;b&gt;Everyone&lt;/b&gt; to ensure easy device discovery. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;For iOS this can be done by going to the &lt;b&gt;Control Center&lt;/b&gt; clicking on the Airdrop option and choosing&lt;b&gt; Everyone&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;For macOS, use the Finder, on the left side bar select Airdrop. From the bottom click &lt;b&gt;Allow me to be discovered by&lt;/b&gt;: and then choose&lt;b&gt; Everyone&lt;/b&gt; from the drop down menu.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1095 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/airdrop-everyone-option.png" alt="" width="300" height="319" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;It is important to also note that for macs that you are actually in the Airdrop option from Finder for your device to be discovered by the sender. In order for Airdrop to work it must be the active location in Finder. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="5"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Distance Between Devices&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Because Airdrop relies on Wi-Fi and Bluetooth technology for connectivity there is a limit to the distance a file transfer can be made from. The range for Airdrop is 30 ft. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Even the distance of 30 ft. is not reliable in a world of ever increasing technology the interference of other devices can be an issue. In some buildings as a security measure walls have been built to block such signals for security purposes. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Even though you may be very close, if you are experiencing problems and the distance is questionable or a wall separates you, reduce the distance and try Airdrop again. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="6"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make Sure the Personal Hotspot is Off (iOS)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Another tip that applies specifically to the current limitations of the iOS part of Airdrop, make sure your personal hotspot is not in use. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;It might because the hotspot is on and that an iPhone or iPad make use of the WiFi that this has been noted as causing interference. Make sure your Personal Hotspot is not on by going to &lt;b&gt;Settings &lt;/b&gt;and making sure the switch is off.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1096 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/disable-hotspot.png" alt="" width="300" height="177" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This might be an even bigger issue if Bluetooth is engaged as well. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="7"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How to Manage Files On Airdrop?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you have been greeted by the message &lt;b&gt;“Cannot receive all of these at items at the same time”&lt;/b&gt;… it would be because the behavior expected of the iOS is to open the app needed for the file type sent and instead, multiple types of files were sent. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;iOS cannot open multiple apps and files at the same time. Different file types like PDF’s, JPG and Docs cannot be sent at the same time. Sending multiple file types to an iOS will fail. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;It is not a difficult fix to make. Just make sure that only one type of file is sent at time to Airdrop at a time by the sender. You should be closer than 30 ft. and able to communicate. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This is different that the macOS. On mac you can receive as many different types of files and as many files at one time as you would like, there is no file limitation. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="8"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Airdropping to Older Mac Computers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Legacy Mac computers have differing Bluetooth versions. Airdrop has been implemented to separate Airdrop protocols. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;One works specifically for Macs produced before 2012&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;The other works for the newer 4.0 Bluetooth &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;The catch is, you have to make sure to turn on this capability if you are trying to send something to an older Mac. The change to this protocol does not happen automatically.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To make the switch, in the Airdrop part of &lt;b&gt;Finder&lt;/b&gt;, select the link in blue that says, &lt;b&gt;“Don’t see who you’re looking for?” &lt;/b&gt;and click on &lt;b&gt;Search for the older Mac &lt;/b&gt;option. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;You should be able to see your recipient on the list now. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="9"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Firewall Settings on Your Mac&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;The massive firewall that comes with macOS can keep Airdrop from working properly. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Although you may think the firewall is off if you share your Mac with another user, they may have enabled the firewall without your knowledge. It is best to make this consideration if at all a possibility. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you or another user has enabled the macOS firewall, this could be the reason your Airdrop doesn’t work and should be turned off. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Just go to &lt;b&gt;System Preferences&lt;/b&gt;, then &lt;b&gt;Security &amp;amp; Privacy&lt;/b&gt;, select the &lt;b&gt;Firewall Tab&lt;/b&gt;. While in the &lt;b&gt;Firewall Options&lt;/b&gt; make sure you uncheck &lt;b&gt;“Block all incoming connections”&lt;/b&gt; and this will re-enable Airdrop. To do this, you will need to have administrator rights on the machine. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="10"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Network Name of Your Device?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you have used a special character when naming your iOS device or Mac, this will disengage Airdrop. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;It is good practice to stick to only alphanumeric characters when naming your new devices. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;On a Mac check this by going to &lt;b&gt;System Preferences&amp;gt;Sharing &lt;/b&gt;and selecting &lt;b&gt;Computer Name. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;On an iOS device got to &lt;b&gt;Settings&lt;/b&gt;, click on &lt;b&gt;About&lt;/b&gt;, click on &lt;b&gt;Name&lt;/b&gt; and you will see it there. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="11"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Additional Troubleshooting Tips for Airdrop&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If nothing has helped so far, try the traditional:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Turn all the devices off and re-start them. A good starting point for most OS issues as well as Airdrop.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Re-start your router. Because Airdrop operates using Wi-Fi a re-boot in overall connectivity may be useful. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Turn the Wi-Fi on and off on both devices and reset the connectivity. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Reset the network setting of your iOS device. This can be done from &lt;b&gt;Settings&amp;gt;General&amp;gt;Reset&amp;gt;Reset Network Settings. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Make sure your software is the latest update available. In general, this is a good idea. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Make sure that the sending and receiving devices are using the same Wi-Fi network. This will make for easier discovery, but is not a must for Airdrop to work. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fixing Problems on Your iPhone, iPad or Mac &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Airdrop has become a huge convenience to and is an awesome way and fast way to share files with a friend or team member on different Apple devices. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;These troubleshooting tips should be the easy fix to your Airdrop problem. If you can’t resolve your problem with these tips, it is time to consult with the experts at the local Apple Store Genius Bar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:55 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:33Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">11+ Ways to Fix Airdrop</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2541" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2541" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2542</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;iCloud is an application on iPads and iPhones that allows its users to store and share data online, like music or pictures, for example. When you use this site, you can access any data you have stored in iCloud through your computer by signing into iCloud.com on your web browser. You can use a Windows or Mac computer; it just needs to be a desktop web browser.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1047 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/Sign-Into-Icould.com-From-Iphone-Ipad.png" alt="" width="560" height="315" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3 class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Setting Up iCloud&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;When you attempt to sign into the iCloud website from an iPhone or iPad, you will see this:&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1044 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/icloud-iphone.png" alt="" width="169" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;This happens because Apple doesn’t want you to access the site from your iOS device when you can easily sign into your iCloud account already. You can sign in by going to your Settings then selecting iCloud.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1045 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/icloud-settings.png" alt="" width="169" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;You toggle the button from “Off” to “On” to begin using iCloud. Then you can easily turn off and on the different features and services iCloud offers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;You should also be using the latest version of iOS or Mac OS when using iCloud to make sure it works properly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Logging into iCloud&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;This is pretty simple to do on both your mobile devices and your computer.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;To login on your iPhone or iPad:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Go to Settings; select iCloud&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Enter your Apple ID and password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;To login on your desktop computer:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Open your web browser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Enter in iCloud.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt; in your address bar&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1046 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/i-cloud-request-desktop.png" alt="" width="169" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Sign in with your Apple ID and password&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;You can also use two-step verification for additional security, where you follow the onscreen instructions then enter a code sent to a trusted device.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Accessing iCloud Files&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;There are two places you can access iCloud: through your iCloud app and through the iCloud website.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;However, you can also check the data and storage available by going to Settings, then iCloud. It is an easy way to toggle which apps will save into iCloud and manage your files.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4 class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recovering Deleted Files&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Sometimes it’s easy to mess up and accidently delete a file. Luckily, you can recover files deleted in the past 30 days on iCloud. Here is what you do:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Sign in on &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;iCloud.com&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Click on Settings&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Under the Advanced option, select Restore Files&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Browse the file list in the Restore Files window and select the files you want back&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Keep in mind files are automatically removed from Restore Files 30 days after they have been deleted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;How Much Storage Is There?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;You automatically start off with 5GB of storage on your iCloud once you set it up. You can use the storage for any of your apps or files, like your photos.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;If you ever need more storage, you can buy more from your Apple device. This starts with 50GB at USD$0.99 a month.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Here are a few tips if you are struggling with your iCloud account:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Make sure you are entering your complete Apple ID when you log in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;You can reset your password if you have forgotten it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;Check the iCloud support website to see if there are any common issue showing up they are working to fix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;That’s all the information I have on iCloud for you today. Hopefully this will be enough information to carry you through your use of iCloud. If not, the Apple support website is always an option to look at!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:57 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:33Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How To Sign In To iCloud.com From iPad &amp; iPhone</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2542" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2542" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2543</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Mac has had Spotlight as a feature for over 10 years. Even though so many fads and interfaces have changed in that time, Spotlight is still widely loved by Mac users. While Spotlight started as a mere tool that let you search your files, it has now become a more complex and advanced asset to users everywhere. It can search for online results and understand complex searches with ease, just as a few examples.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;However, with Apple constantly adding new features to Spotlight and the many new changes over the years, you might not be using it to its full potential. This article will show you the many ways you can use Spotlight on your Mac device, although some do work for iOS devices as well. Try them out and see how it goes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;1. Using Different Search Operators&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;As with many other types of search engines available online, you can specify the type of item you are looking for when inputting your search. It’s easy to limit your search down when using Spotlight: just add “kind: item-type” after you have typed in your search. “item-type” is where you input file extensions, like JPEG, or Apple apps, like reminders and email. You could type in “Christmas kind: JPEG” to see any pictures you have that are labeled Christmas on your computer for example.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;There are even different ways to limit the places Spotlight searches further. For instance, if you only wanted to take a look through your email application, you can begin your search with a date inputted to search for emails received &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;i&gt;after&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt; that date. You would type in “date: DD/MM/YY kind: email” in this case. So, typing “date: 31/10/2017 kind: email” would prompt Spotlight to search for emails after that date.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;There’s even options to search for items created or modified on a certain date and symbols to include in order to narrow down your searches. “created: DD/MM/YY” shows files created on that date while “modified: DD/MM/YY” will show files modified on that date. Using “&amp;lt;” in front of a date will show files before that day, “&amp;gt;” will show files after that date, and “=” will show files on that date.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;This really comes in handy if you are searching for something you can’t remember the name of but know the general time you made it and what application it was in. You might not use this trick daily, but it’s good to know if you use Spotlight often.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Also note that the way the date is written to narrow down your search will vary by the region you are in. So check what your computer displays or what your particular area uses for date displays.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;2. Using Boolean Operators&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1018 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Using-Boolean-Operators.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Boolean operators like “AND”, “OR”, “NOT”, or “AND NOT” can be used to create more complex searches. Boolean operators are usually added onto the end of your search query and can be combined with other operators.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Say you are trying to narrow down the images you are searching through. Maybe you don’t remember if this specific image was in a JPEG or PSD format, for instance, but you remembered the date you uploaded it to your computer. Typing in “date:= 25/12/2015 JPEG OR PSD” would bring up any JPEG or PSD files created on this date so you can easily find the right image.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;3. Getting Instant Answers through Spotlight&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;While knowing how to use various search operators in order to narrow down your searches for specific items is great to know, keep in mind that Spotlight has more functions than just sifting through your indexed files. Most of these instant answers should also work on Spotlight search with your iOS devices also.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;There are many types of things you can get instant answers for! These include:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Instant conversion rates between different types of currency; simply type in the number and the currency in; i.e. “59USD”&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1012 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Instant-Answers-Currency.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="330" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Using Spotlight as a calculator; i.e. “(55-5) *100”&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1013 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Instant-answers-Calculations.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Getting the different scores and schedules for various sporting events by typing in “team schedules” or “score” after the team name or country; i.e. “Australia score”&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1014 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Instant-Answers-Get-match-scores.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="323" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Learning different definitions by just inputting a word; you can jump to the inbuilt dictionary by using CMD+L to show the entry there, if it is available&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1015 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Built-in-dictionary.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="334" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Show the weather of any city by typing in “Weather in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;u&gt;city name&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;”; i.e. “Weather in San Diego, California”&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1016 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Instant-Answers-Get-weather-in-your-city.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Searching through online videos by using the “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;u&gt;search keywords&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt; videos” command; i.e. “The Avengers videos”&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1017 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Search-Keywords-in-video.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="325" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;This isn’t the extensive list of search queries you can make to get instant answers, but the ones listed are great ones to start off with. You can look up more or try inputting some of your own and see what happens!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Keep in mind that any searches that will require Internet – like looking up a team schedule – mean your computer needs Wi-Fi. Other searches options, like using Spotlight as a calculator, don’t need Internet connections to work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;If Spotlight suggestions aren’t working on your device, go over to the Apple website and select Apple support to see if this is an available option in your country.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;4. Natural Language Searching&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1010 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Search-Using-Natural-Language.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="327" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Alright, so maybe the search and Boolean operators are too technical for some to remember to use. If you would rather just input your search more naturally, Mac OS systems after 10.11 El Capitan let you make searches using natural language.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;This more or less means that you can word your search in Spotlight the same way you would if you were talking to another person. For example, instead of putting in the exact date and use the search operators, you can just put in “photos from last year” to search for photos from last year. This is much more simple to use in many cases!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;With the natural language search, you don’t need any special or specific words included in your inquiry. It does limit you somewhat and give you a large selection of files to look through most of the time, but it’s a good addition to the software.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Because it’s natural language, try inputting different types of combinations of words to search for files on your computer. Try it out and see what comes up for you.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;5. Spotlight’s Keyboard Shortcuts&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;I think it is safe to say that we all like to make things easier and faster as much as we can. As with many programs, Spotlight features many different shortcuts that you can use to make it more convenient to use! Here is a list of some of the shortcuts:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+Space Bar brings up Spotlight search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+down arrow lets you jump to the next category of results&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Holding CMD displays the item path for you&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+return will open the location that has the file in it&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+I will open the “Get Info” dialog box for that item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+L jumps to the dictionary listing for a word, if it is listed in the inbuilt dictionary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+B searches the Internet for the search you put in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;CMD+C copies the item from the Spotlight entry without you need to open the file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;6. Searching with Emojis&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1007 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/searching-using-emojis.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="331" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;We know that there are so many different and crazy types of emojis available for you to use, but when do you ever get the chance to even use half of them? Now you have the perfect opportunity to use at least some of them!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;For example, typing in a pizza emoji into Spotlight search will list all of the nearby pizza places. Even a beer emoji will least all of the bars and restaurants that serve beer in your area.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;For those of you who are curious, this works by having each emoji listed with a descriptive name that you can check by going to the Character Viewer. You can access it by using Control+CMD+Space bar. It uses this data in order to interpret the emoji.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;This means that you can use many types of emojis with your search. Try all sorts of emojis with your search and see what comes up! There are many different emojis for you to try and see what comes up in your search results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;7. Searching for apps with initials&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Using Spotlight is a quick and easy way to open up the apps installed on your Mac without having to manually search for them. Sometimes, though, it can be difficult to bother to type in the entire name of an app, especially when the app has a very long name in it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Thankfully, Apple accounted for this and lets you type in initials instead! If an app has multiple names in the title of it, you just type in the initial of each work in the app name and Spotlight still brings up the app.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1006 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/searching-apps-with-initails.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;For instance, you can type in “GPB” to bring up “Google Photos Backup” instead of spending time typing in the whole name. It saves a little bit of time and effort, or a lot of time if the name is very long.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;8. Resizing and moving the Spotlight Window&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;After many years, Apple has finally added on the ability to Spotlight window in El Capitan. In order to resize the window, you should simply drag the cursor from the lower edge of the Spotlight window. The catch is that you can’t make it any smaller than the default size. But you can change the height and position of it on the screen.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1005 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/resize-spot-light.jpg" alt="" width="375" height="207" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;To reset Spotlight to its original position, you just click and hold onto the Spotlight option – the magnifying glass icon – in the menu bar.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;9. Show Results from Select Categories&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1004 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Show-results-from-select-categories.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="473" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Spotlight shows suggestions from many different local and online sources. This is great when it comes to searching for different information from many different places, but sometimes you only want to find information from one type of source.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;To do this in Spotlight, you type in “SP” to open the System Preferences and select “Spotlight.” Here you’ll see a list of different categories Spotlight will look for. Once you see this list, you can uncheck boxes next to the categories you don’t want Spotlight to search in.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;In earlier versions of Mac, you were able to prioritize the categories you wanted Spotlight to search in first.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;10. Excluding a Folder or Disk from Spotlight&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-1003 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/exclude-a-folder.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="454" /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Spotlight indexes most of your internal HDD/SSD drives, including your external hard drives. It may occasionally index other temporary files in your system, which can lead to skewed search results and slow down the speed of the search.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Going to “System Preferences” and choosing “Spotlight” is where you go to fix this problem. Under the “Privacy” tab, you can select the “+” button to add any folder or external drive to what Spotlight will not search for. You can also drag and drop the folders straight into the window.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;If you want Spotlight to be able to search for them again in the future, select the folder from the list and click on the “-” button. The Spotlight will re-index that folder so files and items from that folder will show up in your search results.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Conclusion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;So, there you have it! This was a list of some of the main Spotlight tricks you might want to try out on you Mac at home so you can use it to its full abilities. Knowing how to search with Spotlight efficiently and effectively will definitely be able to help you while you are looking for particular files or doing certain searches.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;Of course, our list doesn’t fully flesh out some of the tips we gave so you had some options to explore. There are also some tips you could use that weren’t included on this list as they aren’t as commonly used or wouldn’t be as commonly useful.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #222222"&gt;What did you think about the tricks we gave you? Have you tried any on your own? Did you even know about some of these tricks? Let us know down below, and let us know what types of things you managed to search for with these tricks!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:57 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:32Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">10+ Tricks for Spotlight on Mac You Need to Know</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2543" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2543" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2544</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To date Google Chrome is the most utilized browser in the world. A title well earned with the number of great features it has to offer. Unfortunately, the best browser is also a monster usage of resources, even more so if you are using an older computer. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;We have all experienced the frustration of being slowed down when using a web browser for work or even personal use. The cause of this might be what you are utilizing and not utilizing in your Google Chrome browser. Some computer users may not know how or where to even look for information on controlling Google Chrome in a more customized fashion. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In some cases if you are an experienced computer user, the lack of speed may out way the performance Chrome can appear to even provide.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;No matter the basis for your desire to speed up Google Chrome, there are a number of ways to provide a faster browser speed for Chrome. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This article is going to cover &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;10 different, simple and effective ways to speed up Google Chrome:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Getting Rid of Un-Needed Extensions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;A number of Chrome extensions operate in the background to maintain the services, much like apps work in the background on a smartphone. You even manage the extensions in a similar fashion as an app on a smartphone. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;As a result, the extensions consume an abundance of operating resources. You might have too many extensions enabled in Chrome (extensions you might not need or be using).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Having an over abundance of extensions operating could easily be the cause of slowed browser speed. The basic fix for this would be to delete or disable the extensions that are not in use. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In order to delete or disable a Chrome extension, click on the &lt;b&gt;hamburger menu &lt;/b&gt;icon in the upper right corner of Chrome, then click &lt;b&gt;“More Tools”. &lt;/b&gt;Then click on &lt;b&gt;“Extensions” &lt;/b&gt;on the side menu.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-959 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Extensions.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="298" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This should direct you to the page the extensions are listed on. Once you have determined which extension you do not want, to &lt;b&gt;disable the extensions&lt;/b&gt;, click in the &lt;b&gt;“Checkbox” beside it. &lt;/b&gt;To completely remove the extension, click on the &lt;b&gt;“Trashcan”&lt;/b&gt; icon beside it.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-960 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Disable-chrome-extension.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="320" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If there are extensions you do not use regularly, we suggest you simply disable them until further needed. If you are unsure if you are using or need an extension, just disable that as well. There is no need to remove or delete extensions unless otherwise determined by your usage.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="2"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enabling Chrome Prefetch&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In order to next guess what link or page you might click on next, Chrome pre-loads them in a cache in the background, to allow the pages to load faster. Obviously this uses more data but it also makes for much quicker browsing.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-961 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Chrome-Setting.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="271" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In order to enable Chrome prefetch, click on &lt;b&gt;“Settings” &lt;/b&gt;in the hamburger menu, choose &lt;b&gt;“Show advanced options”&lt;/b&gt; at the very bottom of the page&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-962 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Enable-Prefetch-on-chrome.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="296" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Click on the checkbox beside &lt;b&gt;“Use a predictive service to upload pages more quickly”&lt;/b&gt;, found under “Privacy”. If your internet plan is limited, we recommend you disable this function. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="3"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Using the Chrome Data Saver&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you have a limited data plan or a slow connection, Chrome Data Saver could make a huge difference for you. Google servers can be utilized by Google Chrome to compress the size of web pages. This compression will make the pages load faster and use less bandwidth. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This feature is not included in Chrome as is, Google offers this Chrome extension as an add on you can install yourself. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Once you install the feature it will automatically start compressing data from web pages as you browse. Please note this extension is not compatible with web pages that are encrypted: web addresses that begin with &lt;i&gt;“https”.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="4"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Change Flash Plugins to Click to Load&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Almost every website these days uses some sort of flash content like ads, videos or some other variety of interactive content. Loading this content can slow a browser down considerably. Aside from being an inconvenience to a power user, such content can be distracting from the task at hand. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;You have the ability to make sure that unless you click on the content, it will not load. This will keep distractions to a minimum, lower bandwidth usage and make Chrome work even better.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-963 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Content-Settings-privacy.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="282" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To make the change to click and load, click on Chrome’s hamburger menu, click on &lt;b&gt;“Content Settings”&lt;/b&gt; under &lt;b&gt;“Privacy”. &lt;/b&gt;Under the &lt;b&gt;“Plugins” &lt;/b&gt;section, scroll down to &lt;b&gt;“Let me choose when to run plugin content”&lt;/b&gt; and select. When this is complete, flash content will only play when you click on it.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-964 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/play-plugins.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="211" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="5"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Disabling Images&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Although this would not be the recommended way to make Chrome faster, it might be the answer for you. There is an option within Chrome that allows you to disable all the images on a webpage, preventing them from loading. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;You might find the images in the content you are interested in to be informative and useful and this may not be the solution for you. If you can live without the images, these are one of the big reasons some web pages take forever to load. If your interest is purely in reading, disabling the images can easily speed the load time of a webpage.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-965 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Disable-Images-on-chrome.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="260" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In order to disable the images in Chrome go to the &lt;b&gt;“Content Settings” &lt;/b&gt;again, under the &lt;b&gt;“Images”&lt;/b&gt; section, select &lt;b&gt;“Do not show any images”.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="6"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Clearing Chrome Data&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Chrome will slow down because of the data it is keeping a hold of, like cached content, browsing history and cookies. If it has been awhile since you have cleared this data, that may be the cause for slowed browsing.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-966 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Clear-Browsing-Data.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="185" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In the Chromes hamburger menu select &lt;b&gt;“History”&lt;/b&gt;, or you can press &lt;b&gt;ctrl+H&lt;/b&gt;, click on &lt;b&gt;“Clear browsing data” &lt;/b&gt;at the top.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Once there check the checkboxes beside the different data you would like removed, click on &lt;b&gt;“Clear browsing data”&lt;/b&gt; and the data will be deleted.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-967 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Select-Data-to-clear.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="387" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;It is not necessary to remove passwords that have been saved and auto fill form information if you make use of these things in your daily browsing. Neither have a huge effect on the browser. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Experimental Features of Google Chrome&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;There are also a few Chrome Experimental Features that can be very useful in speeding up the performance of Chrome. Make note that these features are called experimental for a reason and may not work correctly on computers. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;If you have an adverse experience while using any of these features, you should remove any changes you made and revert to your previous Chrome profile.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-968 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Chrome-experimental-features.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="218" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To find and access the Experimental Features, type &lt;b&gt;“chrome://flag” &lt;/b&gt;in the address bar of your browser and search. Use “Ctrl+F” to find the experimental features touched on in this article. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="7"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Changes to Tile Width and Height&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;By allocating more RAM to height and width, you will make scrolling better and less stuttering while moving through a web page. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Only make this adjustment if you have 4GB of RAM, that should be sufficient.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-969 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Default-Tile.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="289" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;In the &lt;i&gt;Find &lt;/i&gt;dialog type &lt;b&gt;“Default tile”&lt;/b&gt;. There you should find both Default tile width and height options. Using the drop down menus located under them to change from &lt;b&gt;“Default” to 512. &lt;/b&gt;It is also possible to allocate more or less, 512 works best for most people. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="8"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enabling Experimental Canvas Features&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To date this feature is still under development that grants permission to Chrome to use canvases to speed up the loading of a web page. What this may do is eliminate varying types of content when loading a web page. The changes would not be noticeable, they are there.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-970 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Experimental-Canvases.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="252" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;To find &lt;b&gt;“Experimental canvas features” &lt;/b&gt;and click on the &lt;b&gt;“Enable” &lt;/b&gt;button shown below, this will enable the feature. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="9"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enabling Fast Window and Tab Closing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;This feature allows Chrome to appear to be closing tabs and windows faster, when it is really just hiding the process from you while it is happening. Although Chrome is not actually speeding up the closure quicker, the disappearance of the window faster in appearance allows the user to continue browsing during the operation.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-971 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Fast-tab-close.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="252" /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Just search for &lt;b&gt;“Fast tab/window close” &lt;/b&gt;and click on the &lt;b&gt;“Enable”&lt;/b&gt; button shown below, this will enable this feature. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol start="10"&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Enabling QUIC Protocol&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Another work in development, this connection protocol was created by Google to prevent multiple trips to the server in creating a connection. An improvement over UDP, taking less trips to make a connection, is less time spent creating a connection and loading a page. Typically, two or three trips are needed before a connection is secured with a server.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-972 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/QUIC-Protocol.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="283" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Just search for &lt;b&gt;“Experimental QUIC protocol” &lt;/b&gt;and use the drop down menu shown to enable the feature.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Once any of the experimental features mentioned are enabled, you will need to re-launch Google Chrome. Find the “&lt;b&gt;RELAUNCH NOW” &lt;/b&gt;button located at the bottom of the screen and click on it and see if Chrome speeds up.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-973 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Relaunch-Chrome.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="216" /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Notice Any Difference in Chrome’s Performance?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;The ways mentioned in this article should be an adequate and noticeable change in the speed of browsing while using Google Chrome. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;When implementing any of these recommended changes, note how they will change your browsing experience and the affect that may have on your productivity and whether that is a positive or negative. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;We find the most effective ways of increasing the speed of Chrome in this article to be disabling images and setting all plugins for click and play, these settings may not be for everyone. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Although it is doesn’t happen often, keep in mind the experimental features noted here might also have an adverse effect on your browser and slow it down. If your browser does slow down (rare), just set your options back to the defaults.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="western"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: Arial, sans-serif"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium"&gt;Please let us know your thoughts on these methods in the comments section. If you know additional ways to speed up Google Chrome, please share those as well. We would like to keep sharing the tips for other users. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:57 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:32Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">10+ Ways to Speed up Google Chrome for Mac or PC</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2544" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2544" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2545</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Curious how many times your MacBook battery can be charged before it is time for a replacement? Batteries have advanced substantially in energy density and longevity, but it is still a component of your laptop that wears down over time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Apple measures battery consumption in cycles instead of charges. A cycle is fully discharging the battery and charging it back up. For example; if you deplete 50% of your battery every day before charging it back up to 100%, it would take you two days to complete one cycle.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Apple has a support document on their website outlining the expected number of battery cycles each MacBook model is expected to perform before the battery needs replacement. The key takeaway from this document is that Apple&amp;#8217;s laptops made after 2010 are expected to work about &lt;strong&gt;1000 cycles&lt;/strong&gt;, which means that one battery will likely be enough for the lifetime of the computer for most users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check up on your battery health using the MacOS System Information utility:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open Apple menu on the top left of your screen, and select &lt;strong&gt;About This Mac&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;System Report&lt;/strong&gt; button to launch the System Information utility. A new window will appear with a lot of technical specifications about your mac.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Power&lt;/strong&gt; from the left-hand menu under the Hardware list.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-773" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/macos-system-info-battery-power-cycles.png" alt="macos-system-info-battery-power-cycles" width="571" height="528" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, download our favourite battery monitoring App coconutBattery. This free app will give you cycle count for your MacBook as well as your iOS devices. In addition, more detailed battery health metrics are available such as capacity in milliamp hours and temperature, system age, and a way log battery performance over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-774" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/coconutbattery-app.png" alt="coconutbattery-app" width="371" height="602" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:32Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How many times can a MacBook battery be charged?</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2545" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2545" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2546</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Need to record your voice? What is the easiest and best sound recorder on the Mac? If you come a Windows PC background, you may be familiar with a handy little Sound Recorder application. So what options do we have on Mac OS?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally Published April 29, 2011. Updated November 2016. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;QuickTime: The easy option&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-266 aligncenter" title="quicktime_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/quicktime_icon.jpg" alt="quicktime" width="206" height="207" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your Mac is running OS X 10.6 Snow Leopard (2009) or later, you can use the built in QuickTime 10 player for audio recording.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open QuickTime Player from your Applications folder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the File menu and select New Audio Recording.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-765" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/quicktime-new-audio-recording.jpg" alt="quicktime-new-audio-recording" width="600" height="350" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You will see a very simple user interface with sound recording controls.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-766" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/quick-time-audio-recording-interface.jpg" alt="quick-time-audio-recording-interface" width="600" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You may click on the Down Arrow next to the record button to select your sound input (microphone) and sound Quality settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Microphone volume is adjustable with the slider under the record button.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Older Macs will generally have two input sources: Build-in Microphone and a Line-in from the 3.5mm jack. Newer Macs have only the Microphone available as the audio source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline"&gt;High&lt;/span&gt; quality setting records M4A files with variable bitrate using the AAC code. This is good balance of quality, file size and file compatibility. The &lt;span style="text-decoration: underline"&gt;Maximum&lt;/span&gt; quality setting saves AIFC files using PCM S24 codec and produces rather large files. This is overkill in most situations, and file compatibility is limited. If in doubt, use the High setting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note: QuickTime 7 is also built into earlier versions of Mac OS X. However, audio recording was a paid feature of QuickTime Pro.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Audacity: For power users.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-267" title="audacity_icon" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/audacity_icon.jpg" alt="Audacity" width="228" height="219" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How about a free app for recording as well as editing sound? You can also try the free and open source Audacity sound recorder. It is a powerful recorder, editor, and converter. You can find a version that is backwards compatible with macs running much older versions of OS X. It has a steeper learning curve than QuickTime’s audio recording feature, but it is far more powerful and better suited for longer recordings where editing is needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-268" title="audacity_ui" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/04/audacity_ui.jpg" alt="Audacity user interface on a mac." width="450" height="308" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to Audacity’s documentation for an explanation of it’s advanced features.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 12:56 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:31Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to record sound on a mac.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2546" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2546" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2547</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Siri is now available on the Mac with the release of MacOS 10.12 Sierra. After launching on iOS in 2011, it was only a matter of time before the virtual assistant would make it to Apple&amp;#8217;s other major platform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-755"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Using Siri is simple. Apple made three different ways to launch Siri from your desktop:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The MacOS dock:&lt;/strong&gt; The Siri icon is now available in the dock by default.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyboard shortcut:&lt;/strong&gt; Long press Command key + Space will launch Siri in about a second.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Menu bar:&lt;/strong&gt; A new Siri icon is available on the far right corner of the menu bar, next to the notifications icon. The Siri icon can be turned off in system preferences.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what can you do with Siri on the Mac? Pretty much everything you can do on the iPhone, and also some neat file management tricks. Queries like &amp;#8220;Show me my files from yesterday&amp;#8221; for Finder searches, or &amp;#8220;find my selfies&amp;#8221; to perform contextual searches in the Photos app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Research shows that more than half of iPhone users use Siri to perform voice searches. Will the virtual assistant become as popular on the desktop operating system? Only time will tell. What do you use Siri for? Let us know in the comments below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone wp-image-757 size-full" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/siri-mac-example-questions.jpg" alt="siri-mac-example-questions" width="380" height="466" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:31Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to launch Siri on the Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2547" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2547" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2548</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Chances are that you never think of your wi-fi password after your set it up. So how can you recover a saved password from your Mac when you forget it? All you need is your administrator account password.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-741"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open &lt;strong&gt;Keychain Access&lt;/strong&gt; app. It is located in the Applications &amp;gt; Utilities folder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Select the System keychain in the left menu bar, and select Passwords from the category menu. This will filter the keychains to just your stored passwords.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-743" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/mac-kaychain-access-app.jpg" alt="mac-kaychain-access-app" width="480" height="440" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Double click on the name of the network for which you want to view the password.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This will open a new window specific to that stored password. Click on the &amp;#8216;Show password&amp;#8217; checkbox.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-745" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/keychain-access-show-password1.jpg" alt="keychain-access-show-password" width="480" height="313" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You will be asked to authenticate with a username and password. This account must have administrator privileges on your Mac.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-746" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/password-prompt.jpg" alt="password-prompt" width="429" height="210" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; If you are unsure what your username is, open up the Finder app and look for the home icon in the Favorites sidebar. Your home folder will called the same as your username.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-748" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/find-mac-username.jpg" alt="find-mac-username" width="331" height="432" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;After successfully authenticating, the wi-fi network password will be revealed in the previous window.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-747" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/view-password.jpg" alt="view-password" width="480" height="312" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:31Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to find a saved Wi-Fi password on the Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2548" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2548" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2549</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Ever notice how your iOS device will notify you twice about an incoming text message? By default the Messages app will inform you when the text/sms arrives, and once again two minutes later. The idea is to grab your attention in case you were away the first time around. But it can get very annoying, especially if you &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; see it the first time but intend to respond at a later time.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span id="more-736"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;A little known fact is that this can be easily disabled in the iOS Notifications settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="p1"&gt;To turn off repeat notifications from Messages:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;Go to Settings &amp;gt; Notifications &amp;gt; Messages&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;Scroll down and open the &amp;#8220;Repeat Alerts&amp;#8221; menu.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;Check off &amp;#8220;Never&amp;#8221;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-738" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/ios-messages-notifications-settings.jpg" alt="ios-messages-notifications-settings" width="480" height="507" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ll notice the other options are Twice, 3 Times, 5 Times and a whopping 10 Times for the extremely forgetful. Repeated alerts are fired off at two minute intervals. Apple should have really turned this off by default, but now you know how to customize it yourself.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:30Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to turn off repeating Message notifications on the iPhone</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2549" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2549" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2550</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Thanks to the new Continuity feature introduced in OS X 10.10 Mavericks, it is possible to receive and respond to SMS text messages right from the Messages app on your mac. This makes messaging quicker and easier as you can reply from the device that is closest to you. Take advantage of the full size mac keyboard for quickly writing longer texts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span id="more-703"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;You will need to have at least iOS 8 or newer on your iPhone/iPad and OS X 10.10 (Mavericks) on your mac.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;Make sure you are signed into the same iMessage account on your iPhone and in the Messages app on the mac.&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;On the Mac open the Messages app and open Preferences from the menu bar to check your account.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-706 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/message-app-mac.jpg" alt="message-app-mac" width="612" height="478" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;On the iPhone open your Settings and navigate to Messages &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Send &amp;amp; Receive&lt;/strong&gt;, and make sure both your phone number and email address are checked off under &amp;#8220;YOU CAN BE REACHED BY IMESSAGE AT&amp;#8221;.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-707 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/ios-imessage-send-menu.jpg" alt="ios-imessage-send-menu" width="306" height="399" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;On the iPhone go to Settings &amp;gt; Messages &amp;gt; Send &amp;amp; Receive &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Text Message Forwarding&lt;/strong&gt; and select your mac or other device you want to receive SMS on.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-708 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/iphone-text-message-forwarding.jpg" alt="iphone-text-message-forwarding" width="306" height="253" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;Now look back at the Messages app on your mac. You will see a prompt with a security verification code. Enter this code into the iPhone to authorize forwarding to the mac.&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-709 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/mac-messages-verification.jpg" alt="mac-messages-verification" width="417" height="158" /&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-710 aligncenter" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/ios-allow-sms-forwarding.jpg" alt="ios-allow-sms-forwarding" width="306" height="288" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li class="p1"&gt;After successfully entering the verification code you are ready to send and receive SMS on your mac.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:30Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Forward SMS text messages from the iPhone to your mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2550" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2550" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2551</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I hear this a lot. Charge the iPhone in Airplane mode to top it off as fast as possible. Does this actually work out? Is the inconvenience of being disconnected worth the time savings? I was skeptical of these claims, so I decided to find out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-690"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Testing conditions&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using an iPhone 6 with a healthy battery pack I’ve timed 4 charging cycles from 0% to 100%. Two samples for each Airplane mode and Regular (connected) mode conditions. The original Apple Lightning cable and the provided 5 Watt wall charger was used for this test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-694" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/iphone6_charger_usbcabe.jpg" alt="iphone6_charger_usbcabe" width="825" height="540" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h4&gt;Airplane mode&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The phone was switched to Airplane mode prior to being fully drained so it remains in Airplane mode for the duration of the test. I lit up the screen with the home button to check the state of the charge several times during the test.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Regular mode&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wi-Fi, Bluetooth and LTE cellular radios were active for the duration of the test. The iPhone was connected to Wi-Fi, and a FitBit fitness tracker had periodically done data sync over Bluetooth. Several messaging apps were active and sending push notifications, resulting in the screen lighting up. In other words, there was a fair bit more activity on the phone in regular mode. I&amp;#8217;ve fired up all the radios so if there is a measurable difference, I would surely see it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Results&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-691" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/iphone-airplane-mode-charge-times.png" alt="iphone-airplane-mode-charge-times" width="825" height="600" /&gt;It does it fact look like the iPhone 6 will charge on average 9% faster when it is set into Airplane mode. It took on average 11 minutes longer to top off the battery during this test while the phone was online. Whether the marginal time savings are worth being disconnected for two hours depends on the situation and is up to the user to decide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going from 90% to 100% is the longest 10% as charging speed will slow down to prevent damage from overcharging. Keep in mind that you are not likely to have a completely dead phone every time, and if you are in a rush you will probably not be charging to a full 100%, therefore the gap is likely even less significant in real world conditions.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:58 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:30Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Does the iPhone charge faster in Airplane mode?</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2551" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2551" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2552</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;ve undoubtably noticed that one of the subtle changes in iOS 9 is the new lowercase keyboard. When you&amp;#8217;re typing in lowercase (i.e., most of the time), the lowercase keyboard is displayed. However, I&amp;#8217;m not a big fan of this update; the keys don&amp;#8217;t look exactly vertically centred to the eye, and I&amp;#8217;ve grown used to the familiarity of the uppercase keys not only on iOS but pretty much every hardware keyboard ever.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-679"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;The toggle is hidden rather deep in the Settings, so here is how to turn off the lowercase keyboard:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open Settings, go to General.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-682" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/settings-general-ios.jpg" alt="settings-general-ios" width="750" height="120" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the Accessibility menu.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-683" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/accessibility-menu-ios.jpg" alt="accessibility menu ios" width="750" height="120" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keyboard settings. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-684" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ios-settings-keyboard.jpg" alt="ios settings keyboard" width="750" height="120" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Toggle &amp;#8220;Show Lowercase Keys&amp;#8221;.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-685" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/ios-settings-show-lowercase.jpg" alt="ios settings show lowercase" width="750" height="470" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;And you&amp;#8217;re done!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:29Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to bring back the uppercase keyboard in iOS9</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2552" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2552" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2553</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-615 alignright" title="mac-ethernet-port" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/mac-ethernet-port.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;The convenience of wireless networking is fantastic, but it doesn’t compare to the solidity and dependability of a wired network connection.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Where can you find out if your Ethernet connection is running at 10, 100, or 1000 Mbit/s? It is not in the most obvious place, as it turns out.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make sure your Ethernet cable is plugged in, and verify that you are connected to the network in System Preference &amp;gt; Network.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Locate the &lt;em&gt;Network Utility&lt;/em&gt; on your mac. It is in Applications &amp;gt; Utilities &amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Network Utility&lt;/strong&gt;. Alternatively, search Network Utility in Spotlight Search.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-617" title="spotlight-network" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/spotlight-network.jpg" alt="" width="510" height="160" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Info&lt;/strong&gt; tab, under Network Interface, use the drop-down menu to select the Ethernet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You should be able to view network connection details including network addresses, and connection link speed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-616" title="network-utility-mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/network-utility.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="388" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s all there is to it! It&amp;#8217;s obvious after you know where to look. While in the Network Utility, check out other useful features of this app in the other tabs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ping&lt;/em&gt;: Lets you test how long it take to send a message to a remote server and receive a response. Measured in milliseconds.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whois&lt;/em&gt;: Find out who is the registered owner of a domain name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Traceroute&lt;/em&gt;: Trace the path your request physically takes along the Internet when you connect to a remote server.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; Last updated 19th June, 2017, 9:13 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:29Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to check ethernet connection speed on the mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2553" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2553" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2554</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-602 alignright" title="sleeping_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/sleeping_mac.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Want to leave your Mac on for a while for some process to finish? The default behavior in OS X is to put the computer into a low power sleep mode after a couple of minutes of inactivity. While this is great for saving energy, you may find it interfering with your computer usage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Permanent solution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open System Preferences, and go to Energy Saver section.  Here you see two sliders for Computer Sleep and Display Sleep. The sliders range from 1 minute, to Never. Use the sliders to adjust the sleep behavior to suit your needs. If you have a portable Mac, there are separate settings for Battery powered operation and for Power Adapter. You may disable sleep altogether but putting the slider on &amp;#8220;Never&amp;#8221;, just beware that it will increase your energy usage, and likely cause more wear on the system.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-603" title="system_preferences_energy_saver" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/system_preferences_energy_saver.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="344" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-604" title="energy_saver_slider" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/energy_saver_slider.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="420" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Occasional solution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This handy Caffeine app can prevent your Mac from entering sleep mode on demand. An icon in the menu bar will allow you to toggle the setting for those occasional times when you need to computer to run uninterrupted. Click on the cup to toggle Caffeine. System settings apply when the cup is empty, and Caffeine is working when the cup is full. Very convenient and free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-605" title="caffeine_empty" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/caffeine_empty.jpg" alt="" width="120" height="90" /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-606" title="caffeine_full" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/caffeine_full.jpg" alt="" width="120" height="90" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;One time solution&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are familiar with the command line terminal on Mac, OS X Mountain Lion (10.8) has a great new command just for this purpose. As mentioned on AddictiveTips, the &lt;em&gt;caffeinate&lt;/em&gt; command can be used along with a timer set to any length of time you want.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;caffeinate -t 3600&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Where 3600 is the number of seconds in one hour. You may modify it to any number of seconds, or alternatively just enter caffeinate without a timer to disable sleep mode until that terminal window is closed.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 19th June, 2017, 9:15 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:29Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to prevent Mac from going to sleep</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2554" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2554" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2555</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-594 alignright" title="new_macbook_pro_box" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/new_macbook_pro_box.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Generally, most people prefer to buy gadgets early in the product’s life cycle, so it remains “new” for longer. Others prefer to buy a bit later, waiting for any early issues to be worked out. And everyone will agree, that buying right before a major improvement will make you feel at least slightly bitter, because Apple is not known for signalling a product update with a sale. Regardless of your preference, as an informed consumer you can make better purchase decisions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over at MacRumors, they maintain an excellent Buyer’s Guide that keeps track of all Apple product upgrades. It’ll show you the date of the most recent upgrade, and the average number of days between previous updates to give you a rough idea of when you can expect something new. It also conveniently aggregates the latest rumors of what may come of the upgrade. Definitely consult with the Buyer&amp;#8217;s Guide before dropping two grand on a laptop.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Product updates can take two forms; updated internal components that result in performance gains, or a complete product redesign. Apple tipically upgrades Mac specifications once or (rarely) twice a year, these updates are predictable like clockwork. A complete product redesign occurs every few years and is harder to predict, it&amp;#8217;s normally the subject of many rumors and leaks from the supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The timing of any upgrades generally follows by the release of new processors from Intel. In the last couple of years Intel released a new generation of processors in the first half of the calendar year, and Apple incorporates these chips into updated Macs shortly thereafter. When there is a significant improvement, Apple holds special keynote presentations to present their latest creations. Minor specs bumps however, can be released quietly released in a press release.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This year, it’s been reported that Intel will be releasing their brand new family of Haswell processors on June 3rd, 2013. It is therefore widely anticipated that new Macs will be arriving following Apple’s Worldwide Developers Conference (WWDC) on June 10th.&lt;br /&gt; New MacBooks! Yay! Can you tell I’m the early adopter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mac hardware refreshes follow a mostly predictable timeline, this allows the educated consumer to plan their purchase. The same is true for iPhones and iPads, after the annual update pattern is established, Apple will rarely deviate from that path.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:20Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">When is the best time to buy a new Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2555" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2555" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2556</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-529 alignright" title="mac screen recording" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mac_screen_recording.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Do you want to show what you’re doing on your Mac to someone? Or many people? Sometimes video is the best medium to explain what you are doing. You can record your instructions once, and share it on YouTube or social networks. Here is a tip on how to do it for free with Quicktime Player 10, it&amp;#8217;s built-in to Macs beginning with OS X 10.6 (Snow Leopard) and later.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open Quicktime Player, it’s in the Applications folder. You may not see a Quicktime window, but you will see the Quicktime Player menu bar at the top.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-530" title="quicktime menubar" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/quicktime_menubar.jpg" alt="" width="502" height="307" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on File menu -&amp;gt; New Screen Recording.&lt;br /&gt; Now you will see the screen recording window.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-529" title="mac screen recording" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/mac_screen_recording.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the white down arrow to adjust desired settings. You can choose the source for audio, either your built-in microphone, or the in-line audio input. Here you can also select the video quality of the recording, higher quality will lead to larger files.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-531" title="screen record settings" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/screen_record_settings.jpg" alt="" width="502" height="287" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; The Slider below the red record button adjusts the microphone/input sensitivity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the red record button. Now you have the option to record your full screen (default), or you may click to drag a specific area of your screen to crop. The excluded area will be dark.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-532" title="crop screen capture" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/crop_screen_capture.jpg" alt="" width="502" height="314" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; Recording a larger area will result in larger files.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once you selected the area, click to continue. You will now be recording your actions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When finished, click on the stop button, and the video you recorded will now pop up, and you can view it.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-539" title="share to youtube" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/share_to_youtube.jpg" alt="" width="502" height="321" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use the Share button (File menu-&amp;gt; Share) to quickly upload to: YouTube, Facebook, Video and others conveniently right from Quicktime.&lt;br /&gt; Or click on File menu -&amp;gt; Export to make a video file, to submit/share your video manually.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also: If you just want to take a screenshot (picture) of your screen, read this post.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:20Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to record the screen on a Mac for free</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2556" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2556" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2557</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-499 alignright" title="paint_brush_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/paint_brush_mac.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="313" /&gt;Paintbrush is an awesome simple image editor for Mac that mimics the functionality of Paint on Windows. It’s a quick and dirty bitmap based image editor that’s fast and easy to use. There are numerous powerful image editors available for professional level work, but there is something beautifully simple and nostalgic about Paintbrush that makes it fun.&lt;br /&gt; MS Paint has been included in one form or another in every Windows release to date, it has become somewhat of a classic. Interestingly, Apple had its&amp;#8217; own bitmap image editor MacPaint for the original Macintosh that predates MS Paint, but it was discontinued long ago. A very long time ago. This is the void Paintbrush for Mac is trying to fill, and it’s doing a terriffic job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;All the tools work as you’d expect, including the airbrush and paint bucket. Paste images into Paintbrush from your clipboard, or compose quick sketches. Paintbrush supports most common image formats including BMP, GIF, JPEG, TIFF, and PNG.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paintbrush is available for Mac OS X 10.4 or later, it free and open source, get it here.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:19Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Paintbrush, the MS Paint alternative for Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2557" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2557" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2558</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-491 alignright" title="usb_tethering_feature" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/usb_tethering_feature.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Most new Android phones support Wi-Fi tethering, creating a wireless hotspot for sharing the phone’s Internet connection with other devices. Android phones also support USB tethering (unless removed by carrier/manufacturer), which is a nice feature to have when wireless tethering isn’t ideal. In the past the problem has been the lack of USB drivers to connect the phone’s connection to Macs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Now, fortunately there is HoRNDIS. A USB driver developed by Joshua Wise that allows Android’s built-in USB tethering capability to work seamlessly with Mac computers. No rooting, no hacking, or apps required. It just works.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to the HoRNDIS page on Joshua&amp;#8217;s website and download the latest package.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install the .pkg, follow prompts in the installer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plug in your Android phone with a USB cable, and open Settings.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Settings -&amp;gt; Wireless &amp;amp; Networks -&amp;gt; More -&amp;gt; Tethering and portable hotspot&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-492" title="android_usb_tether" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/android_usb_tether.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="316" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Enable USB Tethering, check that box.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now on the Mac, open &lt;em&gt;System Preferences -&amp;gt; Network&lt;/em&gt;. You should see your phone as one of the connections in the list. Like so:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-493" title="system_pref_usb_tether" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/system_pref_usb_tether.png" alt="" width="500" height="435" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You should now be online.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my testing, I was tethering a MacBook Pro with OS X 10.8 connected to a Galaxy Nexus running Android 4.2. The connection was fast, and more reliable than Wi-Fi tethering. The according to the developer, HoRNDIS is working with Mac OS X 10.6, 10.7, and 10.8.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advantages of USB tethering :&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wi-Fi frequencies may be congested in busy locations, slow Wi-Fi.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Charge your phone while tethering.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reduce latency, more responsive connection&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t have to worry about wireless security settings.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:19Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">USB Tethering a Mac to an Android phone</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2558" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2558" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2559</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-465 alignright" title="open_file" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/open_file.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;In some cases it is necessary to change which application is used for a specific file extension. If you found a found a better movie player, text editor, or image viewer you may want to use that application for all files with the same file extension.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, QuickTime Player is the default application for viewing MP4 movie files on OS X, but VLC could be your media player of choice.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Follow these steps to change your default preferences:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find a file with an extension you want to change the defaults to.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Right click on the file to see a menu, and select “Get Info”.&lt;br /&gt; (right click is a two finder click on a trackpad)&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-466" title="get_file_info" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/get_file_info.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A window appears with the file’s information, see the section called “Open with”&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-467" title="open_with_dropdown" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/open_with_dropdown.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It will display the current application used for this file, use the dropdown box to select you new application. If you do not see your new application in the dropdown box, use the &amp;#8220;Other&amp;#8221; selection to browse for it.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="size-full wp-image-468 alignnone" title="change_open_with" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/change_open_with.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the “Change All” button to apply the change to all files ending with the same file extension. That’s all.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-469" title="change_all_button" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/change_all_button.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="300" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Further notes:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;You can always override the default by manually opening the file in a different application with a simple right click, and “Open With” command when the default is not appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make it easier to distinguish between file extensions you may want to also enable the option to make all file extensions visible. In Finder, select Preferences in the top menu, and click on the Advanced tab. Check the box that’s labeled “Show all file name extensions”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-470" title="finder_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/finder_preferences.jpg" alt="" width="250" height="250" /&gt;     &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-471" title="finder_pref_extensions" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/finder_pref_extensions.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:19Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to change the default application for file extensions on Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2559" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2559" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2560</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-460 alignright" title="guest-user-click" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/10/guest-user-click.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;&amp;#8220;Can I use your computer to check something for a minute?&amp;#8221; asks a colleague / stranger.  You could politely refuse, but if you&amp;#8217;re feeling generous you could log your mac into the guest user account in about five seconds without affecting your own open applications.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Assuming that you have the Guest account enabled, it&amp;#8217;s as easy as clicking on your user name in the menu bar (top right) and clicking once more on the Guest User icon. About five seconds later, the computer loads the guest account which is completely independent of your own user account.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;#8217;t have the guest account enabled, it&amp;#8217;s a checkbox in Settings -&amp;gt; Users and Groups -&amp;gt; Guest User. If the settings are greyed out, you will have to click on the lock and authenticate as administrator to modify important system settings. There is no harm in having an active guest account. In fact a guest account would be helpful in allowing a lost/stolen mac to connect to the Internet and become trackable with Apple&amp;#8217;s iCloud and Find My Mac feature.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once your guest is finished, log out of the guest account with the Apple menu (top left) and select Log Out Guest. Or the keyboard shortcut Command + Shift + Q. Keep in mind that files created/downloaded by the guest user are deleted when the guest account logs out. Once the guest accounts is logged out, click on your own account, enter your password, and you&amp;#8217;ll find everything is where you left it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This mac tip was written with OS X 10.8 Mountain Lion in mind, but the steps will be similar on other versions.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:18Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Quickly switch to Guest account user in two clicks</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2560" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2560" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2561</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-405 alignleft" title="dtlmac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/dtlmac.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;That&amp;#8217;s right. Deamon Tools released a beta version of their optical disk emulation software for Mac. The simplicity of the popular Windows PC app comes to Mac OS X, and solves a long standing annoyance. Mounting BIN image files on a Mac.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-403"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Get Daemon Tools Lite for Mac&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disk images are used to create &amp;#8220;files&amp;#8221; out of CDs/DVDs, for archiving, or distributing over the Internet. Macs have long supported ISO images, and DMG images out of the box, but mounting BIN images had been more tricky. Now with Daemon Tools Lite, we have an simple, lightweight app for nearly every disk image format. The current version (as of July 2012) is in beta, and free to download and use. It&amp;#8217;s very stable, and appears to be working without crashing. You can expect that the final release version will be sold for a small fee.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-404" title="dtl_open" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/dtl_open.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="350" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Requires: Mac OS X 10.6 or newer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supports: .b5t, *.b6t, *.bwt, *.ccd, *.cdi, *.bin/*.cue, *.ape/*.cue, *.flac/*.cue, *.iso, *.isz, *.mds/*.mdf, *.mdx, *.nrg, *.pdi&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:18Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Mount bin/cue disk images on a Mac with Daemon Tools Lite</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2561" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2561" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2562</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-396" title="mission_control_ss" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/mission_control_ss.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;In previous versions of OS X, it was possible to have several virtual desktops (spaces) for grouping open applications by activity, and quickly switching between them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;With Lion, Apple introduced one user interface feature Mission Control to replace both Spaces and Exposé. In this new version, full screen apps become separate desktops of their own. But it&amp;#8217;s not entirely obvious how to add your own desktops, like you used to be able to do with Spaces.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-395"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;To add another desktop to Mission Control:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Swipe up with four fingers across the trackpad to reveal Mission Control.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Move your mouse to the upper right corner of the screen and you will see button to create a new desktop.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-397" title="add_desktop" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/add_desktop.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="259" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;To get rid of a desktop, hover the mouse over it for a few seconds and you will see an iOS-like delete button appear on the top left corner.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-398" title="delete_desktop" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/delete_desktop.jpg" alt="" width="233" height="147" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you have your desktops set up the way like, swipe between them quickly using a three finger gesture horizontally across your trackpad. (Or two fingers on the Magic Mouse) You can also rearrange your open applications by dragging them from one desktop to another. You could have a desktop for writing, another one for browsing, and a third for media, etc&amp;#8230; You get the point. Once you get the hang out it, it&amp;#8217;s almost like having an extra monitor.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img class="size-full wp-image-399 " title="mission_control" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/mission_control.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="375" /&gt;&lt;p class="wp-caption-text"&gt;While on any of the desktops, you can go into system preferences to assign a unique desktop wallpaper.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 7:59 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:18Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to add more Mission Control Desktops in Lion</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2562" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2562" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2563</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-387" title="reopen_previous_files" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/reopen_previous_files.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;One of Mac OS X Lion&amp;#8217;s new features is the ability to restore your applications to the state they were in before you closed them. The idea being that if you were to restart your computer, it will resume into the same state as before. Or re-opening a closed application will resume to the previously opened files. Microsoft Word would open with the documents you were editing last, the Preview app will open with the pictures your were viewing previously, etc&amp;#8230; You can probably see how this feature may become more interfering than helpful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this feature to be helpful, you would have to close the files you are working on, before quitting the application. But who does that? Most users tend to just quit the application (Command + Q), but Lion will end up reopening those files on the app next launch. Argh!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Picture this, you&amp;#8217;re opening a JPG to show your boss, and Preview decides to also open other images that you shouldn&amp;#8217;t be viewing at work. Who thought this was a good idea? This functionality bothered me so much, I was regretting my upgrade to Lion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But luckily there is an easy fix!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To disable this annoying behaviour there is just one checkbox to uncheck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type: none"&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open System Preferences&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-384" title="system_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/system_preferences.jpg" alt="" width="45" height="39" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type: none"&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;General (under Personal)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-385" title="general_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/general_preferences.jpg" alt="" width="62" height="60" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li style="list-style-type: none"&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uncheck &amp;#8220;&lt;em&gt;Restore windows when quitting and re-opening apps&lt;/em&gt;&amp;#8220;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-386" title="restore_apps" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/restore_apps.jpg" alt="" width="385" height="29" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s it. Take a deep breath.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 12:57 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:17Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Stop OS X Lion from reopening previous files in applications</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2563" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2563" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2564</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-375" title="trim_enabler_screenshot" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/trim_enabler_screenshot.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Enabling the TRIM command will allow Mac OS X to perform garbage collection on the Solid State Disk (SSD) to optimize write speeds. SSDs are very fast out of the box, but without TRIM, write speeds can gradually decrease over time as the disk becomes slower at overwriting previously used blocks. If your mac came with an SSD from the factory (like those awesome new MacBook Airs), then TRIM is already enabled and you&amp;#8217;re good to go. But if you upgraded to an SSD on your own, and you&amp;#8217;re experiencing slowdowns you may want to read on.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a full background on TRIM, and what it does consult this article.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks to Oskar Groth&amp;#8217;s Trim Enabler app, it has become incredibly easy and safe to get TRIM working with just about any SSD. No need for fussing with command line on the Terminal. Just download the app, flip the switch, and you&amp;#8217;re good to go. But before you check it out, here are three things you need to know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Does your SSD support TRIM? Check the manufacturer&amp;#8217;s website to find the specifications of your specific model, most of the new SSDs on the market today support TRIM.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You need a fairly modern version of Mac OS X. TRIM was added to Snow Leopard in version 10.6.8, so anything newer than that should work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t officially supported by Apple, &lt;strong&gt;so you&amp;#8217;re doing it at your own risk&lt;/strong&gt;. We super strongly recommend that you make a backup of your data before enabling TRIM should something go wrong. You can make a bootable backup, or at the very least a Time Machine backup. You have been warned.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trim Enabler also gives you a handy S.M.A.R.T status readout about your SSD.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-376" title="trim_enabler_smart" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/trim_enabler_smart.jpg" alt="" width="377" height="559" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In case you have to ask: TRIM is only useful for SSDs, if you have a regular hard drive this won&amp;#8217;t improve its&amp;#8217; performance.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:17Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to enable TRIM on a mac with an aftermarket SSD</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2564" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2564" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2565</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-330" title="mac-keyboard-zoom" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/mac-keyboard-zoom.jpg" alt="Command and Plus button" width="350" height="280" /&gt;As someone who reads a lot of content on the web, I commonly come across long articles with small text. You may know that web browsers can change the zoom levels from 100% to larger or smaller, but it&amp;#8217;s a hassle to go into menus to change settings. This quick keyboard shortcut makes zooming in and out a snap. Once you learn this shortcut, you will be wondering how you managed this long without it.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hold down the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Command&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; key and press&lt;strong&gt; &amp;#8220;+&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; to zoom in.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Holds down the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Command&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; key and press&lt;strong&gt; &amp;#8220;-&amp;#8220;&lt;/strong&gt; to zoom out.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hold down the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Command&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; key and press &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;0&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (zero) to reset to 100%.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s compatible with Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, and Apple Safari browsers, and applies the zoom level to all pages on the website. Very Convenient.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While on the subject of zooming, you may also be interested to know that you can zoom in on things using OS X system zoom capabilities. By holding down &lt;strong&gt;&amp;#8220;Control&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; key and scrolling up or down using the mouse. (Two finger gestures on the trackpad)&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:17Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Zooming with Keyboard Shortcuts in the Web Browser</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2565" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2565" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2566</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-321" title="locked-trash" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/locked-trash.jpg" alt="Locked file in trash." width="350" height="278" /&gt;A common problem on a mac is not being able to empty the trash because the files are locked. You get a nasty error message &amp;#8220;&lt;strong&gt;The operation cannot be completed because the file is locked.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#8221; The first thing you should do is check to see the file is open in any of your running applications, close it, and try again. If this doesn&amp;#8217;t help than it may be locked due to some file permissions issues. Here is what to do:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This method will require you to enter some simple commands into the Terminal. The command is used to permanently delete files on your computer, so please be careful.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1&lt;/strong&gt;: Open terminal. It&amp;#8217;s in your Applications &amp;gt; Utilities folder, or you can quickly bring it up through Spotlight search on the top right of the menu bar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-327" title="open terminal" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/open-terminal.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="217" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2&lt;/strong&gt;: In the terminal type in:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;sudo rm -rf&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;followed by a space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-323" title="terminal-rm-rf" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/terminal-rm-rf.jpg" alt="" width="365" height="280" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3&lt;/strong&gt;: Open trash, and drag over your locked file onto the Terminal window. It should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-324" title="drag-file-to-trash" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/12/drag-file-to-trash.jpg" alt="" width="405" height="321" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you&amp;#8217;ve selected the correct file. Hit Enter on your keyboard, and you will be prompted for your account password. Input your password, hit the Enter key again, and you&amp;#8217;re done! Check the trash to see the file is gone.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:17Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to Force Empty Trash on a Mac (locked files)</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2566" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2566" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2567</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-299" title="hide_mac_dock" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/hide_mac_dock.jpg" alt="How to hide mac dock" width="350" height="280" /&gt;It can be a pain to go into System Preferences every time you want to hide the dock. Instead, try this:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hold down &lt;strong&gt;Command&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Option&lt;/strong&gt; keys, and then press the &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; key.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should see the dock slide away. This is especially useful when you want to temporarily hide the dock for extra screen real estate.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 12:57 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:16Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to hide OS X dock with a keyboard shortcut</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2567" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2567" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2568</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-296" title="angry_birds_chrome_webapp" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/05/angry_birds_chrome_webapp.jpg" alt="Play Angry birds on your mac with Google Chrome." width="350" height="280" /&gt;If you can&amp;#8217;t get enough of Angry Birds, or you prefer to experience the addicting physics game on your computer, you&amp;#8217;ll be happy to hear about the free Angry Birds web app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The massively popular game is still dominating the charts on iPhone/iPad app store, and now works on your computer&amp;#8217;s web browser thanks to html5.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game loads in all modern browsers, the it works best in the Google Chrome web browser. The game relies heavily on html5 technologies and heavy scripting, and Chrome has a reputation for very fast script rendering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can simply go to: http://chrome.angrybirds.com/ in your current web browser and start killing pigs right away.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But for the best and smoothest experience, try it out in Google Chrome:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get Google Chrome is you don&amp;#8217;t already have it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Go to https://chrome.google.com/webstore&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Search for Angry Birds, and click Install.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will pin the Angry Birds web app to your &amp;#8220;new tab&amp;#8221; page (like in the image above), so you can launch it from there. Even though it&amp;#8217;s a web app, it is able to save your progress and your scores in your browser without having to log in. How neat is that?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:16Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to play Angry Birds on a mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2568" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2568" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2569</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-259" title="best_media_players_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/best_media_players_mac.jpg" alt="Open Source media players for the mac." width="350" height="280" /&gt;QuickTime/iTunes on the mac is very polished and easy to use, but the media format support is rather lacking out of the box. You can extended its&amp;#8217; media abilities immensely by adding the Perian plugin. But it’s still not as complete as VLC or Mplayer OSX Extended. This MacTip is about free standalone Mac media players that play virtually all types of files. If you prefer simple and powerful apps to unnecessarily bloated ones, you will appreciate these media players.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;VLC: multi-platform Swiss army knife of media playback.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The wildly popular VLC media player has been around for many years, and underwent many incremental improvements to become what it is today. Extremely versatile and easy to use, but packs many advanced features of commercial software. Subtitle support, equalizer settings, and streaming capabilities make this the most complete open source player on the mac.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Get it here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update (February 19, 2012):&lt;/strong&gt; VLC 2.0 was just released. A major update, and it resolves previous performance issues on multi core systems. Can now confidently recommend VLC as the top choice for the mac.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;MPlayer OSX Extended: Packs a bit more punch.&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;VLC is great for most situations, but MPlayer OSX Extended has a secret weapon that helps with HD video playback. If you have an older dual core mac, which is struggling with HD video playback, give Mplayer OSX Extended a try. This media player is multi-threaded, so it’s able to use both processing cores, and offer smoother playback when other media players show choppy video. On a 2.0 GHz Core 2 Duo system, 1080p X264 playback can get choppy with VLC and Perian, but Mplayer doesn’t skip a frame. This has got to be the most efficient X264 player for the mac.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get it here.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:16Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">The best media players for mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2569" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2569" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2570</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-253 alignright" title="how_to_print_as_pdf_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/how_to_print_as_pdf_mac.jpg" alt="Print as PDF instead of printer on a mac." width="350" height="280" /&gt;One of the great advantages OS X has over other operating systems is that Adobe PDF support is built right into the system, and you do &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; need additional software. Right out of the box, you can open, preview, and “print” as PDF documents. And unlike Adobe Reader on Windows, it’s viewing PDFs is very fast on a mac.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-255" title="ms_word_print_menu_pdf" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/ms_word_print_menu_pdf1.jpg" alt="Print menu in MS Word, on a mac." width="300" height="315" /&gt;Almost every application that supports printing will have a PDF button on the bottom left corner of the printing menu.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the File menu and select Print. (Or use the Command + P keyboard shortcut)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;PDF button on the bottom left. Click on this button, and select Save As PDF.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Choose where you want to save the PDF, and give it a file name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Done.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;#8217;t need to have existing printers set up on your mac, and you don&amp;#8217;t need to install special third-party virtual printer drivers. For most people in most situations this PDF support will be sufficient. But you can buy Adobe Acrobat Pro if you need advanced PDF features.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:15Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to Print as PDF file on a mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2570" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2570" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2571</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-248" title="screenshot_box_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/screenshot_box_icon.jpg" alt="Take screenshots with mac kayboard shortcut." width="350" height="280" /&gt;Apple’s minimalist design means that the keyboard only has the keys you need most, everything else is performed with keyboard shortcuts. There is no dedicated printscreen key like you get on PCs, so you will need to resort to a handy keyboard shortcut.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To take a full resolution screen short of entire screen hold down Command and Shift keys, and press the number 3. To take a screenshot of a specific section of the screen, by cropping a box around it, press 4 instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-249" title="mac_screenshot_keyboard_shortcuts" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/mac_screenshot_keyboard_shortcuts.jpg" alt="Hold down Command, Shift and 3." width="213" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This will make a PNG image file on your desktop, and will put the date and time into the file name.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus: &lt;/strong&gt;The PNG format is pretty good for screenshots, because it provides a good balance between file size and image sharpness, but if you prefer JPEGs instead you will need to input two commands into terminal (one by one).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;defaults write com.apple.screencapture type jpg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;killall SystemUIServer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first line changes the screenshot format, and the second line restarts that process that is responsible for actually capturing the image. The default is png, but you can select gif, jpg, tiff, and even pdf.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:15Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to take screenshots on a Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2571" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2571" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2572</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-233" title="max_battery_mac_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/max_battery_mac_icon.jpg" alt="Macbook battery life icon." width="350" height="280" /&gt;Macs already get great battery life. The newest line of MacBooks are supposed to run 7 hours straight without needing a wall socket. But what if you left your MagSafe charger at home, and you know you’ll need 8-9 hour of work?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this MacTip, I’ll list the obvious and not so obvious tips to get the longest possible uptime on a single charge.&lt;br /&gt; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you use it regularly? Really? Most people do not. Yet, it’s on by default and most people don’t bother or don’t know how to turn it off. It’s another wireless radio that uses precious battery power. Switch it off, and keep it off until you need it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-234" title="turn_off_bluetooth_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/turn_off_bluetooth_mac.jpg" alt="Turn off Bluetooth for better battery life." width="230" height="196" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Wifi&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not actively using the Internet? Switch off AirPort. Just like Bluetooth, only this one is more useful and you’ll likely want it back on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-235" title="turn_off_airport_wifi" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/turn_off_airport_wifi.jpg" alt="Turn off Airport wifi when you don't need it." width="269" height="146" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Volume&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mute the sound on your mac unless you really need it. There are various sound notifications made by OS X and your applications. When you’re trying to squeeze the most out of your battery, even the little things matter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-236" title="mute_sound_on_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/mute_sound_on_mac.jpg" alt="Mute the mac." width="215" height="208" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Switchable graphics&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your mac has switchable graphics chips that do not switch automatically, make sure you’re using the better battery life setting. This affects some of the previous 15” and 17”  MacBook Pros. If you don&amp;#8217;t have this option, then you have auto switching graphics or you only have 1 graphics chip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-237" title="select_better_battery_life_under_graphics" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/select_better_battery_life_under_graphics.jpg" alt="Select better battery life." width="381" height="196" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Energy saving setting&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the Energy Saver System Preferences window, make adjustments to reduce wasted energy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-238" title="energysaver_system_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/energysaver_system_preferences.jpg" alt="Adjust energy saver settings." width="450" height="177" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Screen Backlight&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reduce the brightness of your screen as much as you can. But make sure you can still comfortably see, otherwise you’ll put a lot of strain on your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-239" title="reduce_screen_brightness" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/reduce_screen_brightness.jpg" alt="Screen brightness" width="213" height="210" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Keyboard Backlight&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Backlit keyboards are nice. But it’s a luxury item when you’re after long battery life. If you notice that it comes on, either reduce it to the lowest setting, or switch it off and touch type.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-240" title="turn_off_keyboard_backlight" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/turn_off_keyboard_backlight.jpg" alt="Keyboard backlighting." width="215" height="209" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Superdrive&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The optical disk drive eats up the battery on every laptop. It’s got moving parts. Don’t use it unless you absolutely must. Make sure it’s empty, so your mac won’t periodically spin it up to check the contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Close unused apps&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimize the number of active applications.  Even when you are not actively working in the app, it may still be performing background tasks, or communicating with the Internet. Quit the apps you’re not using.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-241" title="quit_unneeded_apps" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/quit_unneeded_apps.jpg" alt="If you don't use it, quit." width="212" height="158" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Install ClickToFlash (or similar)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Flash is very useful, Flash players are very common around the net for video playback. However, Flash also uses a very high amount of system resources, and cuts the battery life substantially. If you’re browsing the web while on battery power, you will want to make sure you’re using something like ClickToFlash for Safari, or Flashblock for Firefox. Flash is blocked, but you can enable individual Flash objects on demand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Avoid doing resource intensive tasks.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Try to prioritize your work so you are doing the light work such as web browsing or text editing on battery power, and leave the heavy duty type stuff such as video conversions for when you’re plugged in. Because let’s face it, if you’re battery goes flat before you reach a charger you can’t do any work at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;External devices&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unplug every external device such as USB thumb drives or external mice, unless you need them. USB, Firefire and Thunderbolt device all draw power from your computer and will have an impact on your battery life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Check battery health.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve followed these suggestions and you’re still getting short battery life you may just be trying to do something very resource intensive. Or it may be time to replace your battery with a new one. Click on the Apple logo on the top left, and select About This Mac. Click on the More Info… button and select Power from the list on the left. You will see the health of your battery, and it will alert you if it’s time to replace it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-242" title="battery_health_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/battery_health_mac.jpg" alt="Check the health of your mac battery." width="417" height="140" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removable batteries can be bought, and swapped by yourself. Integrated batteries need to replaced by Apple.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:14Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to get the maximum possible battery life on a macbook</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2572" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2572" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2573</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-90" title="airport_option_details" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/airport_option_details.jpg" alt="View AirPort details with a click." width="350" height="280" /&gt;If you click on the AirPort icon on your menu bar, you get an overly simple view about your wi-fi connection.  You can see available networks and their signal strength with 4 bars.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-91" title="kayboard_shortcut_option_airport" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/kayboard_shortcut_option_airport.jpg" alt="Option + Click on AirPort in the menu bar." width="223" height="133" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you click on the Airport menu while holding the Option key you get a much more detailed analysis of the Wi-fi connection which is useful if you want to know the exact speed of the connection and signal strength in greater detail than 4 bars.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:00 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:14Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to quickly view wireless network details with a click.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2573" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2573" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2574</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-223" title="burn_app_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/burn_app_icon.jpg" alt="Burn App icon." width="350" height="280" /&gt;We mostly use these drives to import music into iTunes, and ripping DVDs with Handbrake. Although hard drive storage is relatively inexpensive now, it’s still makes sense to record a CD/DVD in some situations.  A DVD disk can store 4.7GB for as little as $0.25, when you buy a spindle of 100. If you give files to a friend on an external hard drive, you will probably want to get the drive back, but with cheap DVDs, you wouldn’t have to care.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are a number of commercial CD/DVD recording solutions for the mac, but they are mostly unnecessary because of an open source app Burn.  It’s completely free to use (donations encouraged), and can easily match commercial products with features.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get Burn here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why it’s great:&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Data Disks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you’d expect, used to make a simple data disk. Useful for archiving your old files, sharing large data files with friends quickly and cheaply.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Note: Burn supports several file systems for data disks, and is set to &lt;strong&gt;Mac (HFS+)&lt;/strong&gt; by default, meaning it is only readable by macs. To make the disk work on Macs, PCs and MP3 CD players, you should select the &lt;strong&gt;Mac + PC&lt;/strong&gt; option from the dropdown menu. I’ve personally wasted many CDs with incompatible file systems, Mac + PC is the safest option.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-224" title="burn_app_data_select_mac_pc" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/burn_app_data_select_mac_pc.jpg" alt="Make sure to select Mac + PC to ensure compatibility." width="393" height="442" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, if you are burning a CD image file like an ISO, or DMG, you should use the Copy feature instead of Data Disk, scroll down to read more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Audio CDs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Burn creates audio CDs with CD text support (80 min), which are compatible with all CD players, and MP3 CDs (700MB). All the necessary format conversions are performed for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Supports common video formats, and records them in VCD, SVCD, DivX and DVD-Video formats. If you plan on playing these disks on computers, or modern media players, you can likely get away with just burning your source file onto a Data disk. This way you won’t have to lose quality with format conversions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Copy Disks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This feature allows you burn your ISO images to a physical disk. But more importantly, it lets you to make a copy of a disk you already have.  Insert the disk into your mac, drag the disk icon onto Burn, and save an image to your computer. Then, insert a blank disk, and drag your saved image onto burn to record your new copy. Very easy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;CDs, DVDs, and optical media in general are on the decline. This is evident as we see more digital distribution via the Internet, and a growing number of computers without optical drives. Also macs do not have Blu-Ray drives, as I suspect Apple is more likely to drop optical media altogether before supporting Blu-ray, as Apple is increasingly more dependent on the Internet for distribution with their iTunes, App Store, and iBooks stores. Fast broadband connections are not available in all geographic areas, so we are still only in the transition process, and until we get to a completely CD-free world, Burn app on the mac will continue to be very useful.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:13Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Use open source Burn app for all your CD/DVD recording needs.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2574" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2574" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2575</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Macs hold their value very well, and it often makes sense to sell yours to help pay for the new model you are lusting after. Or you may be feeling generous, and you want to hand it down to someone needy. One question comes to mind; how do you secure your personal information? You do not want the new owner to have access to your banking information, browser history and chat logs, now do you? You really do not want to just hand it over as is. This MacTip will guide you through the disk erasing and fresh OS install process, so your can rest assured your data is safe no matter where your old Mac ends up. Following these steps will reset the computer to the &amp;#8220;factory&amp;#8221; unboxing state for the new owner to setup and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-192"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update: &lt;/strong&gt;Originally published in March 2011, this guide was updated several times to stay current in light of removal of optical disk drives and updates to Internet Recovery.  Last updated March 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This guide will walk you though erasing your disk, and re-installing a fresh copy of macOS&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Why you need to erase your hard drive/SSD&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you empty your trash bin on your Mac, the files are not really erased. Instead, the reference to the file is removed from the file system (which keeps a list of all the files on your computer), so the computer is able to write new information in the same physical area when space is needed. This is much quicker than rewriting that disk space with blank data, and it also gives you a chance to recover accidentally deleted files with handy recovery software. We recommend erasing the drive with Apple&amp;#8217;s Disk Utility keep your personal data safe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Erasing your storage drive and performing a fresh install using macOS Recovery&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You will need:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A Wi-Fi network with an active Internet connection&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Time. Budget at least an hour for this process, slower Internet connections and older hardware will take longer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s begin!&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Steps may vary with different version of macOS, and hardware configurations but the general idea is the same. We are erasing a 2014 MacBook Air running MacOS 10.12 Sierra, but the steps will be similar with any recent Mac. &lt;span style="color: #000000"&gt;We are assuming you already copied all your data to an external backup, or to your new Mac, because &lt;strong&gt;the following steps will really erase your disk&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Restart your Mac and hold down the following button combination:&lt;br /&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Option + Command + R&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-805" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/internet-recovery-boot.jpg" alt="internet-recovery-boot" width="660" height="400" /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The computer will begin to boot into the MacOS Recovery mode. The macOS Utilities menu will appear after a few minutes. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-806" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/internet-recovery-menu.jpg" alt="internet-recovery-menu" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open Disk Utility to begin the disk erasing process. Select the Internal storage disk in the left-hand menu. It will be called Apple SSD on recent Macs.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-807" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/internet-recovery-disk-utility.jpg" alt="internet-recovery-disk-utility" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Erase &lt;/strong&gt;button at the top of the Disk Utility, this brings up our disk formatting options. MacintoshHD is the default disk name in macOS, disk format required is Mac OS Extended (Journaled), and the Scheme is GUID Partition Map. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-808" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/disk-utility-erase-disk.jpg" alt="disk-utility-erase-disk" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;After erasing the disk you are ready to move on to the operating system installation. An Internet connection is required to download a copy of macOS from Apple. Connect to a Wi-Fi network by clicking on the Wi-Fi icon at the top right of the menu bar.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-810" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/internet-recovery-connect-wifi.jpg" alt="internet-recovery-connect-wifi" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Now that you are connected to the Internet, click &lt;strong&gt;Reinstall macOS&lt;/strong&gt; in the macOS Utilities menu. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-809" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/disk-utility-reinstall-macos.jpg" alt="disk-utility-reinstall-macos" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Follow the install prompts in the installation guide, read and agree the terms and conditions. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-811" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/macos-reinstall-prompts.jpg" alt="macos-reinstall-prompts" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-812" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/reinstall-macos-agree-terms.jpg" alt="reinstall-macos-agree-terms" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When prompted to select an install disk, select the disk that we had just erased. There will only be one option in most cases. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-813" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/select-install-disk.jpg" alt="select-install-disk" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The computer will download a copy of macOS from Apple, and install it on the disk. The system download is several Gigabytes in size, therefore the length of time is determined by the speed of your internet connection.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-814" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/macos-installing-progress.jpg" alt="macos-installing-progress" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once the installation is complete, the Mac will restart and display the factory fresh Welcome screen. At this point your Mac is ready to be handed over to a new owner.  &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-816" src="https://www.mactip.net/wp-content/uploads/2011/03/macos-fresh-install-select-language.jpg" alt="macos-fresh-install-select-language" width="660" height="441" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Unless the new owner is right there already with you, you will probably want to power down the Mac. Press the power button and a dialog box will appear that allows you to shut down.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Give your beloved Mac a good physical wipe down with some dry cloths, and wave it goodbye.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:00Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to securely erase your mac hard drive before selling it.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2575" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2575" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2576</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-185" title="left_side_dock" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/left_side_dock.jpg" alt="Dock on the left side of the screen." width="350" height="280" /&gt;This tip applies to any widescreen mac, but it is especially useful for the 11.6” MacBook Air where the screen is only 786 pixels tall. The 16:9 aspect ratio is even wider than the traditional 16:10 screens found on other mac laptops.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Modern operating systems like Mac OS X and Windows 7 have very tall Docks/Task Bars, and they tend to eat into the vertical resolution of your monitor. Thus your usable desktop space is shorter and wider. On the Mac, you also have to accommodate the menu bar on the top of your screen, so the usable vertical resolution is further wasted. On a typical setup, the large dock and menu bar can easily occupy 90 pixel lines of vertical screen space. On a screen that is only 768 pixels tall, 90 lines is precious screen real estate you could be using more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-186" title="dock_position_comparisson" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/dock_position_comparisson.jpg" alt="You can see much further down a web page with the dock on the side." width="420" height="480" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It may feel unusual at first, and will take so some getting used to. But it is worth the temporary inconvenience. You will be able to see more of a web page without having to scroll. Try it yourself.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;How to do it&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open System Preferences&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on Dock&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Under Position on Screen, select Left of Right&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-187" title="system_preferences_dock" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/system_preferences_dock.jpg" alt="Dock in System Preferences." width="450" height="241" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:15:00Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Use widescreen space more efficiently by moving the dock to the side.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2576" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2576" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2577</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-178" title="refresh_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/refresh_icon.jpg" alt="Refresh icon" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Have you ever impatiently sat in front of your computer hitting the refresh button, waiting for a webpage to update? Check4Chnage is one of my favorite Firefox extensions. It will automate your refreshing for you, and it checks the page for any changes from the previous refresh. Set Check4Change to track a webpage, and go do something else. When changes are detected you will be altered with a sound.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How to use it&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You have Firefox installed, right?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get Check4Chnage extension here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Once you install the extension, it you will be asked to restart your browser.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Then go to a webpage for that you wish to track.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Highlight a paragraph or table you wish to track and right click on it. (On the Mac it’s a two finger click on the trackpad, alternatively you can hold down Control and click)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A menu will appear, and select the refresh period from the Check4Chnage menu.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-179" style="border: 1px solid black" title="check4chnage_start" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/check4chnage_start.jpg" alt="Right click menu appears." width="450" height="254" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Check4Chnage will monitor for changes, and alert you if updates are found. If you want stop, right click again, look on the Check4Chnage menu and select Stop.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;That’s basically all. You may want to optimize Check4Chnage behavior to your specific needs. In Firefox, go to Tools, Add-Ons, select Check4Chnage, and open Preferences. You will find a handful of useful customizations.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-180" title="check4change_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/check4change_preferences.jpg" alt="Check4Change preferences" width="350" height="701" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:59Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Quick tip: How to check webpage for changes with Check4Change Firefox extension.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2577" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2577" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2578</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-149" title="handbrakeicon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handbrakeicon.jpg" alt="Handbrake video converter." width="350" height="280" /&gt;You should never have to pay for video converters. Handbrake is an open source multi-platform app that converts almost any video to iPhone/Apple TV compatible formats.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Why Handbrake&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Handbrake supports almost any video format you can throw at it. It will even rip your DVDs. It’s also crucially supports converting to H.264, which is what we need to play video on iPhone/iPods and Apple TVs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s a multi-threaded application, meaning that your dual core or quad core CPU is put to full use for fastest encoding possible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It’s completely free.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;How&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get Handbrake here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open the DMG, drag Handbrake to Applications folder, and open it up.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The first thing you will asked to select your source file.&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-151" title="handbrake_select_video_source" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handbrake_select_video_source.jpg" alt="Select source video." width="600" height="349" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you don’t want to fiddle with encoding settings you can use the handy preset menu on the right which has a selection of optimized settings. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-152" title="handbrake_presets" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handbrake_presets.jpg" alt="Choose a video preset." width="386" height="303" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take note of the destination location, or change it to your preference.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click the Start button when you’re happy with encoding settings. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-153" title="handbrake_start" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handbrake_start.jpg" alt="Start Handbrake conversion." width="59" height="55" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Your part is done, now wait for the computer to finish, add the completed video to iTunes or whatever you use to manage your video library.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bonus: Converting video formats can take some time even with great software and hardware. If you’re converting more than one video, you may want to queue multiple conversion jobs before starting, so you won&amp;#8217;t have to sit around and wait. &lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-154" title="handbrake_queue" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/handbrake_queue.jpg" alt="Handbrake Queue" width="82" height="48" /&gt;Simply use the Add to Queue button to build your list.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:59Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: Convert any video to iPhone/iPod/Apple TV</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2578" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2578" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2579</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-142 alignright" title="RARs_unarchiver_intro_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/RARs_unarchiver_intro_mac.jpg" alt="How to extract RARs on mac." width="350" height="280" /&gt;Mac OS X already has an Archive Utility app built in, but it’s a capabilities are rather lacking. It only supports extracting from ZIP (.zip), GZIP (.gz), and a number of other less popular formats. There are a few apps like UnRarX and RAR Expander, but my personal favorite is The Unarchiver.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Unarchiver is an open source app. It works seamlessly within OS X just like the built-in Archive Utility but supports a wide range or archive formats, including RAR archives. You don’t need to launch any app to extract archives; simply doubling clicking on your archive, and The Unachiver does the rest.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download The Unarchiver. Requires Mac OS X v10.3.9 or higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another neat fact about The Unarchiver is that if you start extracting from an archive while it’s already working on a different archive, it will wait for the first one to complete before started the second task.  This allows you to queue a set of extracting tasks quickly without slowing down your system.  It may not be an intended feature, but this behavior is really useful because when more than one archive is being extracted, they take longer to complete than having them completed one by one. It’s considerably slower when multi-tasking, this is especially evident with magnetic hard drives and other storage mediums with moving parts and slow seek times.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-143" title="the_unarchiver_preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/the_unarchiver_preferences.jpg" alt="The Archiver Preferences window." width="501" height="387" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you download The Unarchiver and drag it to your Applications folder, launch the app and you will see the Preferences window. From here you can select/deselect the archive format you want it to be associated with. Also, under the Extraction tab, you may select a default directory for output, or you may leave it to ask every time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-144" title="the_unarchiver_in_action" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/the_unarchiver_in_action.jpg" alt="The Unarchiver in action." width="555" height="524" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 1:03 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:58Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to extract RAR archives on mac.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2579" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2579" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2580</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-137 alignleft" title="sms_fun_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/sms_fun_icon.jpg" alt="Sudden Motion Sensor game Tunnel" width="350" height="280" /&gt;If you have a modern portable Mac, it’s likely equipped with Apple’s (SMS) Sudden Motion Sensor technology that is designed to protect the hard drive in the event of an impact.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As it turns out you can do a lot more then save hard drives with this sensor. Here are some apps that creatively use the sensor data for fun.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-131"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tunnel&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Classic arcade game that utilizes the sudden motion sensor to steer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OS X 10.5 and later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download from developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;SeisMac&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-135" title="SeisMac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/SeisMac.jpg" alt="SeisMac app graph" width="390" height="383" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turns your MacBook into a seismograph, measuring acceleration in 3 axis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;OS X 10.4 and later&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download from developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tilt SCREAM Pong&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-136" title="tilt_scream_pong" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/tilt_scream_pong.jpg" alt="Tilt SCREAM Pong" width="400" height="250" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pong, with screaming.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download from developer:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;iAlertU&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Security system app that sounds the alarm when it detect motion or other input. Armed with the Apple remote. Very customizable, can even send email, or run custom scripts if triggered. But note it isn&amp;#8217;t perfect, a computer savvy thief will likely find a way around it. (e.g. plug in headphones)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download from developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Liquid mac.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-134" title="liquid_mac" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/liquid_mac.jpg" alt="Luquid Mac app." width="350" height="272" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Creates an aquarium on your screen. Water particles react to computer motion as if it were a liquid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download from developer.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:58Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: Fun with sudden motion sensor apps</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2580" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2580" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2581</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-118" title="istatpro_dashboard" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/istatpro_dashboard.jpg" alt="iStat Pro screenshot" width="350" height="220" /&gt;Macs are supposed to just work, right? But in case you’re curious, the hardware monitoring widget iStat Pro provides very detailed readings about the inner workings of your computer. iStat Pro makes hardware monitoring painlessly easy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It supports:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;CPU utilization&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Memory utilization&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Networking details&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disk capacity and free space&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Temperature readings from all the sensors&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fan speeds and uptime information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The widget is divided into several sections that read out the most critical information about your mac. You can customize which sections you want to see. It’s the single most complete hardware monitoring solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Get iStat Pro from the official site. (Free, but donations encouraged)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remote monitoring through the iPhone is also available. You&amp;#8217;ll need to get iStat Server (free) for your mac and iStat for iPhone (paid). Details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-119" title="istatpro_tall" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/istatpro_tall.jpg" alt="iStat Pro tall" width="284" height="720" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:58Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: iStat Pro is the only hardware monitoring software you’ll ever need</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2581" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2581" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2582</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-110" title="mac_screen_rotated_90" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_screen_rotated_90.jpg" alt="Screen Rotated 90 degrees." width="350" height="219" /&gt;Sometimes for whatever reason you may need to rotate the screen, unfortunately Apple does not provide an obvious switch. To rotate the screen open System Preferences from the dock, and hold down Option and Command as you click on Displays. This will open the Displays menu with an added Rotation dropdown box with Standard, 90°, 180°, and 270° options.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-111" title="option_command_displays" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/option_command_displays.jpg" alt="Option + Command + Displays" width="430" height="200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-112" title="mac_display_menu_with_rotation" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_display_menu_with_rotation.jpg" alt="Display menu with rotation dropdown box." width="683" height="557" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the above does not work, close System Preferences completely, and hold down Option and Command as you click on System Preferences and then click on Displays without letting go. I can confirm that it works with 10.6.6.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 6th January, 2018, 1:03 AM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:57Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: How to rotate screen on Mac</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2582" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2582" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2583</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-82" title="mac_menu_volume_bar" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_menu_volume_bar.jpg" alt="Mac volume level in the menu bar." width="350" height="225" /&gt;Did you know that you could adjust the volume level on your mac by scrolling with the mouse while the volume bar is open? You can make much more precise adjustments than with keyboard volume buttons. Which can be annoying in noise sensitive environments where 4 squares isn’t loud enough, but 5 squares is too loud.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-83" title="mac_keyboard_volume" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_keyboard_volume.jpg" alt="Keyboard volume adjustment." width="382" height="336" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:01 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:57Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to adjust volume level in small increments.</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2583" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2583" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2584</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-74" title="forcequit_app_beachball" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/forcequit_app_beachball.jpg" alt="beachball" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Nothing is perfect, especially not software. Sometimes for whatever reason you may find that a running application froze and stopped responding to your clicks. This is often accompanied with a spinning beach ball on the mouse. Whether it&amp;#8217;s a bug, or user error, sometimes you need to force quit an app.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could click on the Apple menu on the top left corner, and select Force Quit, at which point you will be presented with a list of running apps, and select the troubled application.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-75" title="mac_apple_menu" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_apple_menu.jpg" alt="mac apple menu force quit" width="371" height="363" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But a much faster way to Force Quit an app is to right click on the icon of the app in the dock (or two finger click on trackpad). You will see a menu pop up above the icon. If you hold down the Option key, you will see the Force Quit option appear. Click on it, and you’re done.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-70" title="mac_force_quit_app_dock" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_force_quit_app_dock.jpg" alt="force quit app by right clicking on icon and holding down option key" width="410" height="363" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:02 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:57Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: Shortcut to force quit a frozen application quickly</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2584" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2584" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2585</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-61" title="appcleaner_icon" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/appcleaner_icon.jpg" alt="mac appcleaner icon" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Macs are famously easy to use, one example is deleting applications. Deleting an application is as simple as dragging the App from your Applications folder to the trash. And it works, but this is not always a thorough way of completely deleting an app. Many apps also save your preferences and other data outside of the Applications folder, which do not get deleted when you drag the App to trash.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span id="more-60"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Get AppCleaner from the official site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is where AppCleaner comes in, it’s a free application that is dead simple to use. When deleting an application, instead of dragging the app into trash, drag it onto AppCleaner and it will locate all the files associated with the app. Hit the delete button, and all those files are moved to Trash.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-62" title="Screen shot 2011-01-25 at 11.50.39 AM" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Screen-shot-2011-01-25-at-11.50.39-AM.png" alt="drag apps onto appcleaner" width="515" height="470" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This ensures that no traces of the application are left on your hard drive that is what we want, unless you plan to reinstall the application later and want to keep your settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-63" title="mac_appcleaner_delete_app" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_appcleaner_delete_app.jpg" alt="deleting an app with appcleaner" width="493" height="451" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:02 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:56Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">How to delete Apps completely with AppCleaner</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2585" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2585" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2586</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-55" title="mac_jdiskreport_pie_chart" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_jdiskreport_pie_chart.jpg" alt="mac jdiskreport pie chart" width="350" height="280" /&gt;Are you running out of space on your hard drive? If you managed to fill up your entire disk, there is a good chance you can free some space by removing stuff you don’t need.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;JDiskReport is a handy multi-platform application that scans your entire hard drive and generates colorful pie charts to show you what is hogging all your disk space.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get JDiskReport from the official site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you open JDiskReport on the mac, you will be presented with several scan options like so:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-56" title="mac_jdisk_report_menu" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_jdisk_report_menu.jpg" alt="mac jdisk report start menu" width="547" height="445" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scan a file tree:&lt;/em&gt; Scan a specific folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scan /&lt;/em&gt; : Scan the whole computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scan /Users/yourname:&lt;/em&gt; Scan your user folder.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scan a previously saved scan&lt;/em&gt;: Self explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once the scan is completed you are able to click on individual slices to drill down and see which files are taking up the most space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because this procedure includes permanently deleting files from your computer, I would strongly recommend you stick to scanning only your user folder ( /Users/yourname ) unless you know exactly what you’re doing. You do not want to accidentally delete important system files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is generally safe to delete files from the user folder, but avoid deleting from the /Users/yourname/Library folder as it may contain your preferences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you find a big file or folder you want to delete, open that location in Finder and delete the file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Update: Read the AppCleaner MacTip about removing Applications properly.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:02 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:56Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: Check what is taking up the most space on your hard drive with JDiskReport</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2586" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2586" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2587</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-31 alignleft" title="macosx_cmd_tabbing" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/macosx_cmd_tabbing.jpg" alt="mac osx cmd tab" width="350" height="276" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;An easy way to switch between different open applications on Mac OS X is by holding the command key and pressing  Tab. But you may have noticed this switches only between open Applications. What if you have more then one open instance/window of the running application? How to you quickly switch  between two open Word documents?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is how:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="size-full wp-image-32 alignnone" title="keyboard_cmd_switcher" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/keyboard_cmd_switcher.jpg" alt="mac keyboard cmd switcher cmd + &amp;#096;" width="241" height="223" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To switch between two instances of the same application (between two Preview windows for example) try the &amp;#8220;Command + `&amp;#8221; combination. It’s the key right above the tab key on the mac keyboard. This allows you to switch between two windows of the same app, and works with most applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-33" title="mac_keyboard_control_ctrl_tab" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/mac_keyboard_control_ctrl_tab.jpg" alt="mac keyboard control + tab for browser tab switching" width="241" height="223" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another time saving shortcut is “Control + Tab” within a web browser. This allows you to quickly switch between open tabs. Works in Safari, Firefox, and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bit awkward at first, but a real time saver once you get the hang of it.&lt;/p&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:02 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:55Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: How to Tab between open Apps like a pro</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2587" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2587" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
    <ns0:entry>
        <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="Tips" />
        <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post" />
        <ns0:id>post-2588</ns0:id>
        <ns0:author>
            <ns0:name>test</ns0:name>
        </ns0:author>
        <ns0:content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-20" title="volume_level" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/volume_level.jpg" alt="Mac OS X volume level" width="259" height="233" /&gt;You must be familiar with what I&amp;#8217;m talking about. That sound you hear when you change the volume level on your mac. It&amp;#8217;s neat at first, but overtime I&amp;#8217;ve grown tired of it, and it just attracts unwanted attention.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here is how to disable it:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Open System Preferences from your dock. &lt;img class="size-full wp-image-22 alignnone" title="system preferences" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/system-preferences.png" alt="system preferences icon" width="52" height="45" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Click on the sound menu. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-23" title="sound menu" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/sound-menu.png" alt="mac sound menu" width="56" height="56" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Uncheck the &amp;#8220;Play feedback when volume is changed&amp;#8221; check box. &lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-24" title="volume-feedback-menu" src="https://45.33.89.23/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/volume-feedback-menu.jpg" alt="mac volume feedback menu" width="676" height="492" /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Done. Enjoy the peaceful quiet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt; Last updated 24th October, 2017, 8:02 PM</ns0:content>
        <ns0:published>2018-02-02T05:14:55Z</ns0:published>
        <ns0:title type="html">Tip: Disable volume change popping sound</ns0:title>
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2588" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
        <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2588" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /></ns0:entry>
</ns0:feed>
