<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ns0:feed xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <ns0:title type="html">BotPress</ns0:title>
  <ns0:generator>Blogger</ns0:generator>
  <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  <ns0:updated>03.12.2017 08:27</ns0:updated>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-3097</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Call on your Summoner to battle along-side minions in the free-to-play MOBA. Level up, buy upgrades from the store and play cooperative with some friends. League of Legends has a lot of competitive action and fighting as you slaughter minions, turrets and Summoners.League of Legends has received a lot of attention in the Linux world. WineHQ's and PlayOnLinux are constantly bombarded with questions on how to run it.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing League Of Legends in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Official Website version of League Of Legends.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 17.3 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.10Wine:  1.8Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  1.8Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 1.8 is installed and you can close this windowCreate AccountGo To:  https://login.leagueoflegends.com/Click "Create an Account"Click preferred languageFill out registration formClick "Play For Free"Download League Of Legends InstallerLeagueOfLegendsBaseEUW (Europe West)http://l3cdn.riotgames.com/Installer/SingleFileInstall/LeagueOfLegendsBaseEUW.exeLeagueOfLegendsBaseEUNE (Europe Nordic East)http://l3cdn.riotgames.com/Installer/SingleFileInstall/LeagueOfLegendsBaseEUNE.exeLeagueOfLegendsBaseNA (North America)http://l3cdn.riotgames.com/Installer/SingleFileInstall/LeagueOfLegendsBaseNA.exeNavigate to DesktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "Install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName the virtual drive:  leagueoflegendsClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 1.8Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextWine ConfigurationApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows XPGraphics TabCheck "Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windows"Check "Emulate a virtual desktop"Desktop size:  Enter resolution of Linux DesktopClick OKPlayOnLinux Packages (Libraries, DLL's, Components)Check the following:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextNote:  All packages should automatically download and installInstalling League of LegendsClick BrowseNavigate to your DesktopSelect "LeagueOfLegendsBaseNA.exe"Click OpenClick Next againClick NextCheck "I accept the terms..."Click NextSelect "Complete"Click NextClick InstallUncheck "Launch League of Legends"Click FinishPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect "lol.launcher.exe"Click NextName the shortcut:  League Of LegendsClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureBack to PlayOnLinuxSelect "League of Legends"Click ConfigureGeneral TabWine version:  1.8Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of Wine.Display TabVideo memory size:  Select the amount of memory your video card/chip usesClose ConfigureLaunching League of LegendsSelect League of LegendsClick RunNote: Click Debug to see errors and bugsClick AcceptClick AcceptUpdating &amp; PatchingPeer to Peer disableClick the gear at the top rightUncheck "Allow Peer to Peer Transfer"Click LaunchLoginCheck "Remember username"Click PlayOptimizationPress EscClick OptionsClick VideoAdjust:ResolutionWindowed ModeGraphics PresetsCharacter QualityEffects QualityEnvironment QualityShadowsCharacter InkingFrame Rate CapAnti-AliasingWait for Vertical SyncClick OkayConclusion:League of Legends runs even better with Wine 1.8 I've read you may experience better performance with Wine 1.8-staging as well.  I had no problems with my GeForce 550 Ti 192-bit 1GB RAM.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>02.12.2017 06:24</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">League of Legends Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=7942" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=4287" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-7927</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Protect your bases by slaying dinosaurs in large prehistoric maps.  Upgrade your weapons and abilities to get the upper-hand and cooperate with friends while you take down Dinosaur bosses. With many different multi-player modes and bots for pratice... Orino Prelude isn't your typical First Person Shooter.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Orion Prelude in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Steam version of Orion Prelude.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 18.3 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.12Wine:  3.0Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  3.0Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 3.0 is installed and you can close this windowDownloading SteamGo To:  http://www.steampowered.comClick Install SteamDo not click "Install Steam Now"It will automatically install Linux SteamSelect Windows Steam insteadclick "Windows" under the green buttonNavigate to your desktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  orionpreludeNo spacesClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 3.0Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextConfigure WineApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck:  Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windowsClick OkPlayOnLinux Packages (Libraries, Components, DLL's)Check the following libraries:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_d3dx10POL_Install_tahomaPOL_Install_vcrun2008POL_Install_vcrun2010Click NextNote: All packages will automatically download and installInstalling SteamClick BrowseNavigate to your desktopSelect:  SteamSetup.exeClick OpenClick NextClick NextCheck:  I accept the license...Click NextClick NextClick NextClick InstallClick FinishUpdating SteamClick the "X" to close Steam loginPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect Steam.exeClick NextName your shortcut:  Orion PreludeClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureBack to PlayOnLinuxClick ConfigureGeneral TabArguments:  -no-dwrite -no-cef-sandboxThis fixes any missing font problems and the Store problem (Windows needs to be set as Windows XP)Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of wineDisplay TabVideo Memory Size:  Select the size of Memory your video card/chip usesClose ConfigureLaunching SteamSelect Orion PreludeClick RunNote:  Click debug to see errors and bugsClick "Login to existing account"LoginFind Orion Prelude in your Steam Libraryclick InstallUncheck "Create desktop shortcut"Uncheck "Create start menu shortcut"Click NextClick finishWait for Orion Prelude to finish downloadingClick PlayOptmizationClick OptionsClick VideoAdjust:FOVGammaAspect RatioResolutionFullscreenVertical SyncBloomDepth of FieldMotion BlurSpeed Tree LeavesDynamic LightsDynamic shadowsVehicle ParticlesWeapon ParticlesCharacter ParticlesEnvironmental ParticlesMax AnisotropyAntialisingShadow QualityFoliage QualityCharacter TexturesWorld TexturesConclusion:Orion Prelude ran perfectly after I installed Dotnet.  Normally UDK or Unreal Engine games have a Dot Net Framework distributable bundled with the installer, but not all of the games use it.  Orion Prelude definitely uses it and won't launch without it.  After connecting to an online game, if you experience some frame lag, try lowing some of the settings like anisotropy or antialising.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>21.11.2017 18:52</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Orion Prelude Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=1894" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=5472" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-5209</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Ever wondered who cleaned up all the mess after your hero slays all the minions and bad-guys?  Well you can...  Play Viscera Cleanup Detail and work countless hours cleaning every blood stain, severed limb and broken object.  Remember, everything has to appear as if nothing every happened.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Viscera Cleanup Detail in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Steam version of Viscera Cleanup Detail.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 18.3 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.12Wine:  2.0.3Note:  Also runs in Wine 3.0Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  2.0.3Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 2.0.3 is installed and you can close this windowDownloading SteamGo To:  http://www.steampowered.comClick Install SteamDo not click "Install Steam Now"It will automatically install Linux SteamSelect Windows Steam insteadclick "Windows" under the green buttonNavigate to your desktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  visceracleanupNo spacesClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 2.0.3Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextConfigure WineApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck:  Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windowsCheck:  Emulate a virtual desktopDesktop size:  1024x768Click OkPlayOnLinux Packages (Libraries, Components, DLL's)Check the following libraries:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaPOL_Install_vcrun2010Click NextNote: All packages will automatically download and installInstalling SteamClick BrowseNavigate to your desktopSelect:  SteamSetup.exeClick OpenClick NextClick NextCheck:  I accept the license...Click NextClick NextClick NextClick InstallClick FinishUpdating SteamClick the "X" to close Steam loginPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect Steam.exeClick NextName your shortcut:  Viscera Cleanup DetailClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureBack to PlayOnLinuxClick ConfigureGeneral TabArguments:  -no-dwrite -no-cef-sandboxThis fixes any missing font problems and the Store problem (Windows needs to be set as Windows XP)Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of wineDisplay TabVideo Memory Size:  Select the size of Memory your video card/chip usesInstalling Dotnet45 ManuallyMiscellaneous TabClick "Open a Shell"Copy/Paste:Code:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>14.12.2017 03:13</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Viscera Cleanup Detail Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=9831" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=5916" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-3137</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Drakensang is free-to-play MMO RPG and only requires a few minutes to setup.  The download is literally under 10 Megabytes and the game loads in seconds.  If you want to play a quick game with stunning graphics, intense minion skirmishes and cooperative gameplay (PvE &amp; PvP)... Drakensang is the best place to begin!Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Drakensang in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Drakensang Online version of Drakensang.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 17 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.5Wine:  1.7.39Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version: 1.7.39Note:  Try using stable Wine 2.0 and 2.0-stagingSelect itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 1.7.39 is installed and you can close this windowDownload DrakensangGo to:  http://www.drakensang.comClick "Play Now"Create a new account, or login with your existing accountDo not click download because Chrome will try to download a .dmg file.Copy and paste this link:https://drasaonline-481-dwl.bpsecure.com/applet/dro_setup.exeNote:  Link may not work because of the setup version.  I right clicked the download button, selected "copy address" then renamed .dmg to .exeSave "dro_setup.exe" to your DesktopPlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "Install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  drakensangClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of wineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 1.7.39Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextWine ConfigurationApplications TabWindows version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck "Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windows"Check "Emulate a virtual desktop"Desktp size:  Set to match the resolution of your Linux desktop (for fullscreen)Click OKInstalling Packages (Libraries, Components, DLL's)Check the following:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextClick BrowseNavigate to your desktopSelect DrakensangOnlineSetup.exeClick OpenClick NextClick NextClick "I Agree"You will probably see this error"Certificate import failed:  Unable to add certificate to certificate store"Click OkUncheck "Run Drakensang Online"Click FinishPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect "thinkclient.exe"Click NextName your shortcut:  DrakensangClick NextClick NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureSelect DrakensangClick ConfigureGeneral TabWine version:  1.7.39Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine. Click the down-arrow to select other versions of wine.Display TabVideo memory size:  Select the amount of Memory your video card/chip usesClose PlayOnLinux ConfigureLaunching DrakensangSelect DrakensangClick RunEnter your username and passwordNote:  There will be updates from time to time and the game will ask if you want to install them at this screen.  Click Yes and allow it to install.Click LoginClick Play on the server recommended for your locationOptimizationSetting FullscreenClick the square on the tip right to set fullscreenClick the three bars on the top rightSelect SettingsClick the eye for video settingsTurn on/off:Full-screen qualityHigh graphic qualityBlood effectsShadowsSSAOClick the green checkmark to applyConclusion:I absolutely love Drakensang! I have been playing Drakensang on and off for over a year and have leveled up two characters to level 31.  The graphics are amazing, the installation is quick and it runs on almost any hardware.  With WINE 1.7.39 it will crash about every hour, but you just have to kill it and then launch again.Drakensang is truly an addicting game with great boss fights, random encounters with other characters and unlimited loot.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>29.12.2017 16:35</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Drakensang Online Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=9158" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=0174" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-5343</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Star Trek Online is set in the year 2409, thirty years after the events of Star Trek: Nemesis.Each character is captain of their own ship and can choose between three factions:FederationKlingonRomulanImmerse yourself in sci-fi third person action, tactical space combat and exploring the galaxy in a beautifully rendered world of Star Trek.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Star Trek Online in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Downloaded version of Star Trek Online.  Steam and Arc versions may require additional steps.Note:  March 2017 Perfect World Entertainment ended support for Windows XP and Direct X 9. This guide no longer applies until we can pursue more testing in Wine.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 17 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.8Wine:  1.7.43Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  1.7.43Note:  Try using stable Wine 1.8 and 1.8-stagingSelect itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 1.7.43 is installed and you can close this windowDownload Star Trek Online ClientGo To:  http://download.perfectworld.com/sto/star_trek_setup.exeSave the star_trek_setup.exe in a folder on your desktopPlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "Install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  startrekonlineClick NextCheck all three:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 1.7.43Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextWine ConfigurationApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck "Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windows"Check "Emulate a virtual desktop"Desktop size:  1920x1080 (or enter the resolution of your Linux desktop)Click OKInstalling Packages (Components, Libraries, DLL's)Check the following:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextNote: All packages will automatically download and installInstalling Star Trek OnlineClick BrowseSelect the star_trek_setup.exe from your desktop folderClick OpenClick Next againClick OKClick NextClick "I Agree"Click NextUncheck "Create a desktop icon"Click InstallUncheck "Launch Star Trek Online"Click FinishPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect "Star Trek Online.exeClick NextClick Next againSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureSelect "Star Trek Online"Click ConfigureGeneral TabWine Version:  1.7.43Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine, click the down-arrow to select other versions of WineDisplay TabVideo memory size:  Enter the amount of memory your video card/chip usesClose ConfigureLaunching Star Trek OnlineSelect Star Trek OnlineClick RunLauncher UpdateLog in with your account credentials (or register)Star Trek Online Launcher will download and patch the entire game:  9 GigabytesClick EngageCryptic Loading ScreenWhen you launch Star Trek Online the first time, you will have to wait about 15-20 minutesAfter that it launches fairly quickLogin AgainSometimes the login will fail and you have to login againOptimizationClick OptionsDisplay TabAdjust windowed or fullscreenAdjust refresh rate and antialiasingGraphics TabUse Render Quality and Graphics Detail sliders to adjust graphicsOr manually set:ScreenDetailEffectsLightsAdvanced TabMore settings to increase/decrease performanceRule of ThumbHigh settings = More detail, lower frame ratesLow settings = Less detail, higher frame ratesConclusion:Star Trek Online ran really well on my Geforce 550 Ti.  I rarely had any issues with loading, controls or diplay settings.  The game actually pre-set everything to High and the game is beautiful.Every once in a while the mouse would not turn your character/ship completely around, but a quick right-click fixes it.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>08.01.2018 12:52</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Star Trek Online Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=8426" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=7229" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-6417</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Build the city of your dreams or build the city you live in.  In Cities XL Platinum you can select maps from continents across the world in many different environments. Micromanage the economy, workers, entertainment, marketplace and more... there is always something to build.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Cities XL Platinum in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Steam version of Cities XL Platinum.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 18.3 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.12Wine:  2.0.3Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  2.0.3Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 2.0.3 is installed and you can close this windowDownloading SteamGo To:  http://www.steampowered.comClick Install SteamDo not click "Install Steam Now"It will automatically install Linux SteamSelect Windows Steam insteadclick "Windows" under the green buttonNavigate to your desktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  citiesxlNo spacesClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 2.0.3Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextConfigure WineApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck:  Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windowsClick OkPlayOnLinux Packages (Libraries, Components, DLL's)Check the following libraries:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextNote: All packages will automatically download and installInstalling SteamClick BrowseNavigate to your desktopSelect:  SteamSetup.exeClick OpenClick NextClick NextCheck:  I accept the license...Click NextClick NextClick NextClick InstallClick FinishUpdating SteamClick the "X" to close Steam loginPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect Steam.exeClick NextName your shortcut:  Cities XL PlatinumClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureBack to PlayOnLinuxClick ConfigureGeneral TabArguments:  -no-dwrite -no-cef-sandboxThis fixes any missing font problems and the Store problem (Windows needs to be set as Windows XP)Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of wineDisplay TabVideo Memory Size:  Select the size of Memory your video card/chip usesClose ConfigureLaunching SteamSelect Cities XL PlatinumClick RunNote:  Click debug to see errors and bugsClick "Login to existing account"LoginFind Cities XL Platinum in your Steam LibraryClick InstallUncheck "Create desktop shortcut"Uncheck "Create start menu shortcut"Click NextClick FinishWait for Citie XL Platinum to downloadClick PlayOptimizationClick OptionsClick VideoAdjust:Video QualityResolutionAnti-AliasingPlanetWaterShadowsParticlesClick OKClick AdvancedAdjust:LifeTexturesBuildings DistanceTrees DistanceFurnitures DistanceVehicles DistancePedestrians DistanceClick OKConclusion:Cities XL Platinum ran perfectly without any real problems.  When you launch the game, be patient, it can take about a minute to start the intro videos.  After that it runs GREAT on my GeForce GXT 1060.  I noticed it can slow down in large cities with the distance settings cranked up to high.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>28.11.2017 14:21</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Cities XL Platinum Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=2945" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=3916" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-4576</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Diablo 3 is the long awaited successor to Diablo 2.  We all waited 12 years to see what Blizzard Entertainment would conjure up to renew the franchise.  It was well worth the wait!  Return to the town of Tristram with new classes, weapons, loot and beautiful graphics.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Diablo 3 in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Battle.net version of Diablo 3.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 17 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.10Wine:  1.8* Successfully runs in Wine 2.0.3Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  1.8Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 1.8 is installed and you can close this windowDownloading Battle.netGo to:  www.battle.netClick "Get the desktop app for Battle.net"Click DownloadClick WindowsNavigate to your desktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "Install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName the virtual drive:  diablo3Click NextCheck all three options:Use another version of wineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 1.8Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextWine ConfigurationApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows XPGraphics TabCheck "Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windows"Click OKPlayOnLinux Packages (DLL's, Libraries, Components)Check the following:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextNote:  All packages will automatically download and installInstalling Battle.netClick BrowseNavigate to your DesktopSelect "Battle.net-Setup.exe"Click OpenSelect LanguageClick ContinueUncheck "Add desktop shortcut for Battle.net"Click ContinueAn error about Battle.net Helper.exe will pop upBattle.net installation will crash, but its still installedUncheck "Send to Blizzard"Click ClosePlayOnLinux ShortcutWait for the shortcut dialog to appearSelect "Battle.net.exe"Click NextName your shortcut:  Diablo IIIClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureSelect Diablo IIIClick ConfigureGeneral TabWine version:  1.8Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of Wine.Display TabVideo memory size:  Enter the amount of memory your video card/chip usesInstalling Visual C 2015Miscellaneous TabClick "Open a Shell"Copy/Paste:Code:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>24.12.2017 22:18</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Diablo 3 Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=1738" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=9657" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
  <ns0:entry>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://www.blogger.com/atom/ns#" term="LinuxGames"/>
    <ns0:category scheme="http://schemas.google.com/g/2005#kind" term="http://schemas.google.com/blogger/2008/kind#post"/>
    <ns0:id>post-4612</ns0:id>
    <ns0:author/>
    <ns0:name>amdin</ns0:name>
    <ns0:content type="html">Dear Esther is the most graphically beautiful game made in the source engine. Who is the narrator?Who is your character on this remote island?How can such a beautiful place exist?Explore an abandoned island and cave systems with poetic narration and admire the exquisite landscapes.Follow my step-by-step guide on installing, configuring and optimizing Dear Esther in Linux with PlayOnLinux.Note:  This guide applies to the Steam version of Dear Esther.  Other versions may require additional steps.Tips &amp; Specs:To learn more about PlayOnLinux and Wine configuration, see the online manual:  PlayOnLinux ExplainedMint 18.3 64-bitPlayOnLinux:  4.2.12Wine:  2.0.3Wine InstallationClick ToolsSelect "Manage Wine Versions"Look for the Wine Version:  2.0.3Select itClick the arrow pointing to the rightClick NextDownloading WineExtractingDownloading GeckoInstalledWine 2.0.3 is installed and you can close this windowDownloading SteamGo To:  http://www.steampowered.comClick Install SteamDo not click "Install Steam Now"It will automatically install Linux SteamSelect Windows Steam insteadclick "Windows" under the green buttonNavigate to your desktopClick SavePlayOnLinux SetupLaunch PlayOnLinuxClick InstallClick "install a non-listed program"Click NextSelect "Install a program in a new virtual drive"Click NextName your virtual drive:  dearestherNo spacesClick NextCheck all three options:Use another version of WineConfigure WineInstall some librariesClick NextSelect Wine 2.0.3Click NextSelect "32 bits windows installation"Click NextConfigure WineApplications TabWindows Version:  Windows 7Click ApplyGraphics TabCheck:  Automatically capture the mouse in full-screen windowsCheck:  Emulate a virtual desktopDesktop size:  1024x768Click OkPlayOnLinux Packages (Libraries, Components, DLL's)Check the following libraries:POL_Install_corefontsPOL_Install_d3dx9POL_Install_tahomaClick NextNote: All packages will automatically download and installInstalling SteamClick BrowseNavigate to your desktopSelect:  SteamSetup.exeClick OpenClick NextClick NextCheck:  I accept the license...Click NextClick NextClick NextClick InstallClick FinishUpdating SteamClick the "X" to close Steam loginPlayOnLinux ShortcutSelect Steam.exeClick NextName your shortcut:  Dear EstherClick NextSelect "I don't want to make another shortcut"Click NextPlayOnLinux ConfigureBack to PlayOnLinuxClick ConfigureGeneral TabArguments:  -no-dwrite -no-cef-sandboxThis fixes any missing font problems and the Store problem (Windows needs to be set as Windows XP)Note:  Click the + to download other versions of Wine.  Click the down-arrow to select other versions of wineDisplay TabVideo Memory Size:  Select the size of Memory your video card/chip usesClose ConfigureLaunching SteamSelect Dear EstherClick RunNote:  Click debug to see errors and bugsClick "Login to existing account"LoginGo to your Steam LibraryFind Dear EstherClick InstallUncheck "Create desktop shortcut"Uncheck "Create start menu shortcut"Click NextClick FinishWait for Dear Esther to downloadClick PlayOptimizationClick OptionsClick VideoAdjust:BrightnessAspect RatioResolutionDisplay ModeLaptop Power SavingsDetail FoliageDetail Foliage Draw DistanceField of viewClick ApplyNote:  Click Advanced for more settingsRule of thumb:High settings = More detail, lower frame ratesLow settings = Less detail, higher frame ratesConclusion:Initially I tested the native Linux version from Humble Bundle and there were always dependencies missing.  I spent over an hour trying to find the right libraries, install them or link to newer one's and it was too confusing.  Some of these older libraries are no longer supported and are very difficult to setup.  So I decided to try it in PlayOnLinux and it worked perfectly in a 32-bit virtual drive.  No problems and great performance.Gameplay Video:Screenshots:</ns0:content>
    <ns0:published>16.01.2018 05:36</ns0:published>
    <ns0:title type="html">Dear Esther Guide</ns0:title>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=0142" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <ns0:link href="http://localhost/blog/?p=3063" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
  </ns0:entry>
</ns0:feed>
